<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hodinkee</title>
    <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 09:02:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <description></description>
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On: The Patek Philippe Cubitus In 40mm</title>
      <dc:creator>Malaika Crawford</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 13:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-patek-philippe-cubitus-in-40mm</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-patek-philippe-cubitus-in-40mm</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>A slightly downsized Cubitus captures exactly where we are on the watch-design timeline.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8ec3722c-c884-4681-8fea-727025a0a639/20250404_PatekPhilippe_010.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	<p>Patek Philippe is the Swiss custodian of high watchmaking. Think ref. 1518, 1526, 2523, 2499, etc. Today, broadly speaking (i.e., outside of watch enthusiast circles), Patek is best known for being the maker of one product: the Nautilus — a model so sought-after, so embedded in the cultural vernacular, that its presence is nearly inescapable. The Nautilus is worn by crypto bros and hedge funders, rappers and record execs, tech founders, movie producers, athletes, art collectors, and international moguls — anyone who moves fast, spends big, and wants the world to know it.</p>
  	<p>Herein lies the paradox of a product so successful that, to preserve the very scarcity that fuels its desirability, production must be curtailed. How does a brand sustain commercial success when its business model depends on exclusivity? It's the question every luxury house is scrambling to answer. Patek Philippe discontinued its steel 5711 Nautilus in 2022.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Patek Cubitus watch " src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/f7d28586-3fcb-4858-a086-658e692c37a5/20250404_PatekPhilippe_014.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Late last year, <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/introducing-patek-philippe-cubitus-collection" target="_blank">a new square-shaped collection</a>, aptly named Cubitus (the first new collection from Patek Philippe in 25 years), caused a stir among watch enthusiasts and collectors alike. The Cubitus was, in the eyes of the watch community, the Nautilus reborn, a silhouette so reminiscent of its predecessor, it could only be described as a close cousin. Released in 3 references, the 5821/1A-001 is crafted in stainless steel with an olive green sunburst dial powered by the automatic Caliber 26-330 S C; the 5821/1AR-001, steel and rose gold with a blue sunburst dial, offering the same movement; and the 5822P-001, a platinum version with added complications — a grand date, day display, and moon phase — driven by ultra-thin caliber 240. The Cubitus was Patek's signal that a new collection was being brought into the fold. There were loud complaints, long-winded diatribes, impassioned rants, and scattered praise. In short, emotions were stirred and feathers were ruffled.</p>
  	<p>And then, rather predictably, the dust settled. Orders for the Cubitus came in — from clients untouched by the noise, and from enthusiasts who had once barked slander but were now singing a different tune. Like anything new, desirability doesn't always come as an immediate response. Sometimes the most successful designs are the ones that initially meet the strongest wave of disdain.</p>
  	<p>The first time I saw a Cubitus was in a shopping mall in Taipei last October. The kind of mall where the floors are gleaming white and the elevators occupy lengthy vertical stretches as far as the eye can see: A polished temple of luxury. And there she was, the very divisive green-dialed 5821/1A, sitting proudly in the window. I was politely informed that all three models on display were reserved for clients and that touching, let alone trying on the watches, was strictly prohibited. I found the watches far less jarring than I had prepared myself for. I had no visceral reaction whatsoever (rare, if you know me). In person, it was just another steel sports watch. I proceeded to the food court downstairs to eat soup dumplings and get on with my life. As if Cubitus always was.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Cubitus on wrist " src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a7b8ba7d-631e-4979-8a89-c1f78509bc4c/20250404_PatekPhilippe_007.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/7a83ce33-6482-4a8b-ac8d-8a00e2ff1c9e/20250401_PatekPhilippe_034.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/97420970-b03e-435c-b3cb-42e777e3b973/20250401_PatekPhilippe_037.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>Five months after the initial Cubitus release, two new 40mm time-only references were introduced at Watches and Wonders: ref. 7128/1R rose gold with a brown dial and ref. 7128/1G in white gold. The (largely anticipated) smaller diameter case was reminiscent in size of the ref. 3800, a model long heralded by vintage enthusiasts. As a Ref. 3800 fan (or downsize me to 3900/1J, I'm not picky), and as a woman with relatively small wrists, naturally the 7128 spoke to me more than the initial rather gargantuan in my opinion 45mm.</p>
  	<p>I am not usually one to throw around disparaging remarks about larger case sizes, but 40mm is just a better fit for a larger cross-section of wrists. The 45mm Cubitus is a lot of watch, and when seen from a bird's-eye view (like all watches are!), often extends beyond the top of the wrist. A 40mm square is bold but wearable for most. I proceeded to try on my first Cubitus in the hallowed halls of the Geneva Palexpo: The rich square chocolate brown sunburst dial sat in perfect harmony with its pink gold case, warm tones that felt reassuringly retro within its more brutal, modernist square case shape. The blue and white gold is certainly cooler in tone and different in feeling, but wearable nonetheless.</p>
  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/e9222c43-2457-47c6-bd97-0f7e59a76172/20250401_PatekPhilippe_004.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a74bdbd5-8f4f-44c4-80fb-ebed4e016171/20250401_PatekPhilippe_006.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Patek Cubitus watches" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/863620ae-99a7-408b-958d-e2679dd32d30/20250404_PatekPhilippe_010.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Powering both models is the self-winding Caliber 26-330 S C/434, visible through a square sapphire caseback and finished with a rotor engraved in the same horizontal pattern as the dial. The movement features hacking seconds and a date display. No notes on the bracelet. It remains unchanged from the Nautilus, and rightly so. Why alter something that already borders on perfection? Ergonomically, the Nautilus bracelet has long been considered industry-leading: fluid in its articulation, balanced in weight, and almost impossibly comfortable on the wrist. Both the rose gold 7128/1R and the white gold 7128/1G are priced at $76,590 at retail. </p>
  	<p>The Cubitus has been positioned by Patek as a sort of spiritual successor – a chance to reset the narrative, appeal to a new generation, and play with form while referencing the past. Those with stronger feelings may say it's the Nautilus remixed through 2025 chaos culture. Whether you're gung-ho and see this as a sentimental nod to the golden age of sport watch design, or you dismiss it as a laughably incremental update to its cushion-shaped predecessor, it still marks an evolution in the Patek Philippe catalog.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Cubitus on Ben Clymer" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/fcf6fbd0-9920-4c97-91c3-142df6849a82/20250401_PatekPhilippe_024.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2bf44d4c-f9aa-4698-afff-0024511ad669/20250401_PatekPhilippe_008.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/0e30d9d0-9d73-47f7-a4e2-7b3978da74e8/20250401_PatekPhilippe_017A.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>There's something noteworthy about the introduction of a new design language into Patek Philippe's catalog – one that feels almost alien to the rest of the brand's portfolio, largely due to its sharply squared case. While the Cubitus stands apart visually for being square, there are historical touchpoints that provide context. References like the 5020 or the 5035, though more obscure, share a similarly unconventional geometry. The 5020 in particular – known for its tonneau-shaped case – feels like a predecessor, part of a broader lineage of Patek models that deviate from classical round forms. Framing the Cubitus within this lineage gives it a historical grounding; it makes the watch feel less like an outlier and more like a continuation of Patek's more experimental side.</p>
  	<p>Above all, the Cubitus serves as a timestamp for the current watch consumer landscape. Cubitus is a big shiny mirror reflecting our consumer habits and tastes right back to us. Firstly, Cubitus proves our unrelenting reliance on Genta–inspired design. There is absolutely no escaping it. We are a consumer culture stuck on sport watches, much like we are stuck on athleisure. Athleisure is no longer a fashion statement in and of itself, but has faded into every corner of apparel. The same can be said of stainless-steel sports watches, which we simply cannot move past.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Cubitus on Malaika Crawford " src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/871db538-caa0-41a9-9c8b-54d087e93452/20250404_PatekPhilippe_004.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>There's no escaping the pervasive 'hype' that surrounds these highly sought-after models – a symptom of a culture that feeds on social media wealth signaling, often at the expense of personal expression. Hype cuts across every consumer category, though rarely with the fevered intensity of the pandemic-era frenzy that saw steel 5711s selling for over $130,000. We live in a Louis Vuitton–monogrammed world, where luxury watches now appear on red carpets, recognized even by those far outside the nebulous world of watch collecting.</p>
  	<p>The sport watch has become the calling card du jour for all brands. The major players within the luxury industrial complex feed the beast – responding not with any sort of intellectually challenging vision, but by echoing the desires of the consumer. Why would any luxury brand C-suite stray too far from a proven commercial success in these uncertain times?</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Cubitus rose gold" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/10b9f431-0bde-46f4-b4d8-93d69479b5a0/20250401_PatekPhilippe_033.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Outside of commercial desirability, there's the inner sanctum of the watch world, eager for something new, yet seemingly blind to the fact that everything they're now rehashing and parading as unusual was once just as ubiquitous. Everything we wear, from clothing to jewelry to watches, is cyclical. Trends belong on a timeline. What the Cubitus proves is that there is a safety and familiarity in design codes. It represents a certain visual language that signals taste, status, and identity. "While these codes evolve over time, many of the most powerful ones from the 1970s still hold sway, even as they begin to show their age," explains Michael Friedman, founder of the soon-to-be-released watch brand Pattern Recognition. "The watch industry, historically geared toward an older demographic, is now seeing those same buyers – particularly older Gen X – nearing retirement. For them, watches that channel 1970s aesthetics aren't just stylistic throwbacks; they're generational touchstones. Just as Boomers showed a strong preference for midcentury design and 1950s tool watches, this cohort now turns to the era of luxury sports watches as a symbol of their own peak."</p>
  	<p>The Cubitus and watches similar to it lean heavily on a design language that may be approaching the end of its cultural cycle. The reference points are clear and increasingly nostalgic. And yet, it's precisely that nostalgia – and the power of those still-resonant codes – that continues to drive desire. As we near the 50th anniversary of the Nautilus, perhaps the Cubitus marks the final iteration of heavily Gérald Genta–influenced designs. Perhaps Cubitus is the final chapter?</p>

<p>For more information, visit <a href="https://www.patek.com/" target="_blank">Patek Philippe online</a>. </p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8ec3722c-c884-4681-8fea-727025a0a639/20250404_PatekPhilippe_010.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Hands-On: The Patek Philippe Cubitus In 40mm</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bring a Loupe: The 2025 Geneva Spring Auctions And A Few eBay Gems</title>
      <dc:creator>Rich Fordon</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/bring-a-loupe-may-9-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/bring-a-loupe-may-9-2025</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>All that and more in this week's edition of Hodinkee's What's Selling Where column.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d198cae6-6147-4d16-9158-be34038ca3ec/BAL5.9.25_HERO.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	<p>Welcome back to Bring A Loupe, and happy Geneva Spring auction weekend Friday! That's right, in this edition we'll focus on a few of the 1,292 lots under the hammer in Switzerland's second-most populous city. But if you're a fan of the more obscure eBay picks, in the words of the great Hawk Harrelson, sit back, relax, and strap it down — a few gems are waiting for you at the end of the article.</p>
  	<p>But first, as always, results! It was a white glove week for our humble column, all five moving on to new watchboxes. The incredible Movado "Disco Volante" chronograph sold at the asking price of <a href="https://www.goldfingersvintage.com/watches/p/1940s-movado-m90-disco-volante-pulsations-dial-rare" target="_blank"><u>$18,995</u></a>. On eBay, our Polerouter "Broad Arrow" finished at <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/326551979898" target="_blank"><u>$7,100</u></a>, and the Swatch Black Friday chrono sold for <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/256888902335?_skw=swatch+black+friday&amp;epid=16037213858&amp;itmmeta=01JTR4JHPMMRC6EGRAZVW0VMBY&amp;hash=item3bcfc592bf:g:AWAAAOSwaWVnIU5P&amp;itmprp=enc%3AAQAKAAAA0FkggFvd1GGDu0w3yXCmi1eE049jyjeOzRyMFaFDdqT5dCcR%2FLWh38%2FVusk0CmLViqq%2F6H0GM%2Fj3nhY0f3FsnDPwRhnvpUJYOOYZumqP3cmnZaik2S3IoMAc2bj1fQnPfo%2BklblDxGcuxep1M9X9bLuVBg1Le10iVFemWhLKQKak6%2F0vnAsNdaC6Aoa%2FhCpxYYKbpUoKDKzKzz0tht%2B5VB5JgHKyFNIBVjNfY%2F3OGQM4ibJyffvgLu8WVlKjbDPypPfd1bZHFyon6ceoN6%2FgX2o%3D%7Ctkp%3ABk9SR8abyoTWZQ" target="_blank"><u>$175</u></a> in short order. The week-old Rolex OP 41 with a Pistacio dial finished at <a href="https://loupethis.com/auctions/rolex-oyster-perpetual-41-134300-pistachio-green-dial" target="_blank"><u>$20,900</u></a> on Loupe This. Finally, that quirky Marvin found a new home for <a href="https://www.craftandtailored.com/products/1950s-marvin-dress-watch-14k-rg-gilt-dial" target="_blank"><u>$1,250</u></a>.</p>
  	<p>If you're interested in following the big auctions from home, the greatest spectator sport in the watch world, the schedule is as follows:</p>
  	<p><a href="https://uhren-muser.de/en/catalogue" target="_blank"><strong>Dr. Crott Auctioneers - 112th Auction</strong></a></p>

<p>Saturday, May 10th, 6am ET</p>

<p><a href="https://www.phillips.com/auction/CH080225" target="_blank"><strong>Phillips - The Geneva Watch Auction: XXI</strong></a></p>

<p>Saturday, May 10th, 8am ET</p>

<p>Sunday, May 11th, 8am ET</p>

<p><a href="https://live.antiquorum.swiss/auctions/1-AGSAQW/important-modern-vintage-timepiece-antiquorum-geneva" target="_blank"><strong>Antiquorum - Important Modern &amp; Vintage Timepiece</strong></a></p>

<p>Saturday, May 10th, 8am ET</p>

<p>Sunday, May 11th, 8am ET</p>

<p><a href="https://www.sothebys.com/en/buy/auction/2025/important-watches-part-i-ge2501?lotFilter=AllLots" target="_blank"><strong>Sotheby's - Important Watches: Part I</strong></a></p>

<p>Sunday, May 11th, 5am ET</p>

<p><a href="https://www.christies.com/en/auction/rare-watches-featuring-stories-in-time-a-collection-of-exceptional-watches-23915-gnv/" target="_blank"><strong>Christie's - Rare Watches, Featuring Stories in Time: A Collection of Exceptional Watches</strong></a></p>

<p>Monday, May 12th, 7am ET</p>
  	<h2>Dr. Crott — 1985 Patek Philippe Ref. 2499/100 "Fourth Series" Retailed By Gübelin</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A Patek 2499/100" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ac055d48-8f9b-49d0-aafe-863af35bf809/BAL5.9.25_Crott2499_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Dr. Crott Auctioneers.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Okay, I lied. Not all the auctions featured here are in Geneva — whatever, it's my column. <a href="https://uhren-muser.de/en/catalogue/61000" target="_blank"><u>This Patek 2499, lot 155</u></a>, at Dr. Crott in Mannheim, Germany, was too good to ignore, and there is a particular dearth of 2499s and 1518s on offer in Geneva this season!</p>
  	<p>"New old stock" or "NOS" is a moniker thrown around all too often in the collector watch world, especially by auction houses. That being said, this example does appear to be exactly that. If you're ever evaluating a billed-as NOS 2499 in the future, come back to this watch and compare — this is what it should look like. The dial is perfect, the case is clearly unpolished with extra crisp hallmarks, the list goes on and on. To round out the package here, this watch is accompanied by its original box and papers, has the correct buckle, and likely original Patek strap; it has everything going for it. The Gübelin stamp on the dial makes this one all the more special, tying it to one of the world's foremost Patek Philippe retailers. The estimate has been set at €500,000 - 1,500,000.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="A 1920 Audemars Piguet jump hour" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/08307a36-260e-49bd-89e7-05d1665e909e/BAL5.9.25_AP_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Dr. Crott Auctioneers.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>A bonus pick from Dr. Crott is <a href="https://uhren-muser.de/en/catalogue/61294" target="_blank"><u>lot 159</u></a>, a 1920s jump hour Audemars Piguet. If you know vintage AP well, you know just how rare this watch is, and it dates back to the period of Art Deco wristwatch experimentation. It's a timeless design now, but would have been quite off the wall in 1925. Check out the rest of the catalog <a href="https://uhren-muser.de/en/catalogue" target="_blank"><u>here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>Phillips — 1961 Vacheron Constantin Piece Unique Minute Repeater Ref. 6448 In Platinum</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A 1961 Vacheron repeater" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ba1268f5-db33-475e-9844-aed701e9d892/BAL5.9.25_PhVC_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Phillips.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Phillips has the most noteworthy vintage watch in what is frankly not the most attention-grabbing of Geneva auction seasons. This Vacheron ref. 6448 (<a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/vacheron-constantin/216799" target="_blank"><u>lot 57</u></a>) was produced in 1961 as the brand's final minute repeater before a decades-long break. Between this watch and the early 1990s, VC made zero repeaters. There are three known examples of this reference, this being the only one in platinum. The white gold one did quite well as Phillips in November of 2022, selling for CHF 541,800. And the one on offer this weekend is almost arbitrarily better. It's fresh to market from the family of the original owner in Mexico, in absolutely perfect condition, and, if you're in the market, well worth going the distance for.</p>
  	<p>That white gold 6448 was <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/found-an-oversized-ultra-thin-minute-repeating-vacheron-cons" target="_blank"><u>covered on Hodinkee all the way back in 2012</u></a>. Much of what Ben wrote then applies to this weekend's 1960s Vacheron repeater, but this is technically better. If there is one watch I wish I had made the trip to Geneva for, this is it. The estimate has been set at CHF 120,000 - 240,000.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="A 1961 Vacheron repeater" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/0e2f92ab-29c2-4fe8-bdd9-be243cd9b8d3/BAL5.9.25_PhVC_2.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Phillips.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Also at Phillips, and worth paying attention to, is a <a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/f.p.-journe-x-tha-for-breguet/216337" target="_blank"><u>Breguet Pendule Sympathique produced by F.P. Journe in 1991, lot 18</u></a>. Referencing a 1795 Abraham-Louis Breguet invention, the complicated master clock automatically winds and sets the time of the tourbillon wristwatch when docked. Breguet commissioned this for the "Art of Breguet" auction in Geneva on April 14, 1991. Technique Horlogère Appliquée (THA) – Journe, Denis Flageollet, and Vianney Halter –collaborated to produce it, and the final price back then was <a href="https://catalog.antiquorum.swiss/en/lots/lot-174-204" target="_blank"><u>CHF 1,546,250</u></a>.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="A breguet clock and watch" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/4c92b489-49df-4c03-ad13-c36adeab4a22/BAL5.9.25_PhBreguet_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Phillips.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/93cbff19-662b-4063-8925-7923c6184325/BAL5.9.25_PhJourne_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Phillips.</i></p></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ce78e679-0766-4ce6-b7b3-e359d5074e0d/BAL5.9.25_PhBrette_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Phillips.</i></p></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>Speaking of Journe, keep an eye on <a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/f.p.-journe/212424" target="_blank"><u>lot 116, a "Ruby Heart" Tourbillon Souverain</u></a> that is getting a ton of attention. And don't overlook <a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/simon-brette/216175" target="_blank"><u>lot 14, the Simon Brette Chronomètre Artisans</u></a><a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/simon-brette/216175" target=""><u>,</u></a> the first example to hit the auction market as <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/three-hot-watches-including-a-yellow-gold-rolex-daytona-le-mans-and-a-simon-brette-are-coming-to-auc" target="_blank"><u>covered by Andy Hoffman right here on Hodinkee</u></a>. Check out the full catalog <a href="https://www.phillips.com/auction/CH080225" target="_blank"><u>right here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>Antiquorum — 1939 Patek Philippe Calatrava Ref. 530 In Steel With Rose "Salmon" Dial</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A patek 530" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/01be62f4-da86-4080-9260-979f17182a4d/BAL5.9.25_AQ530_2.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Antiquorum.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>As Calatravas continue to drive collector enthusiasm, Antiquorum is offering the best option of the season. This ref. 530, <a href="https://live.antiquorum.swiss/lots/view/1-AGSD2U/patek-philippe" target="_blank"><u>lot 773</u></a>, was produced in 1939, the second production year for the reference, and has just about the most ideal dial and case configuration you could dream up. It is fresh to market from the collection of "an Italian Gentleman," according to the auction house. The 530 is the upper echelon of vintage Calatravas. They are 1.5mm larger in diameter than the more standard ref. 570 and ultra rare. So rare that collectors barely knew they were real until a letter from Patek surfaced in 2004 confirming that some time-only 530s were made (typically, the reference number is used for chronographs).</p>
  	<p>In particular, Breguet-numeral 530s go crazy at auction. The record price for a 530 was set in 2016 for a steel case, black Breguet-numeral dial at <a href="https://www.phillips.com/detail/patek-philippe/CH080116/135" target=""><u>CHF 1.4m</u></a> — we'll see how this one stacks up. The dial has been cleaned, as is obvious by the clearly removed and put back on a bit cooked numerals, but this is a watch about rarity. The estimate has been set at CHF 200,000 - CHF 400,000.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="A vacheron from the 1930s" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2e2a0421-eee6-4faa-81d9-2671a50210af/BAL5.9.25_AQVC_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Antiquorum.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>If you're less interested in six or possibly seven-figure Pateks, Antiquorum's vast catalog has 790 lots on offer. My vintage-Calatrava biased eye was drawn to <a href="https://live.antiquorum.swiss/lots/view/1-AGSCJE/vacheron-constantin" target="_blank"><u>lot 423</u></a>, a nice little Vacheron option from 1939, at an estimate of CHF 3,000 - CHF 5,000. Check out the entire catalog <a href="https://live.antiquorum.swiss/auctions/1-AGSAQW/important-modern-vintage-timepiece-antiquorum-geneva" target="_blank"><u>right here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>Sotheby's — 1971 Rolex Daytona "Panda Paul Newman" Ref. 6263</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A Rolex Daytona 6263 Newman dial" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/c44bf53b-2554-4ce2-8be4-7fb099fec175/BAL5.9.25_SB6263_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Sotheby's.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>A vintage Rolex near and dear to my heart, the 6263 "Panda Newman" is an undisputed grail. The combination of screwdown pushers, black bezel, and two-tone, clean black and white Newman dial makes up what many collectors consider a perfect watch. Just a few months back, I traced the history of this exact watch at auction in an <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/by-the-numbers-rolex-oyster-paul-newman" target="_blank"><u>in-depth study</u></a> of the market, and this is the first exceptional example to come up since. The market isn't exactly ripping for this type of thing, so it'll be interesting to watch. This example, <a href="https://www.sothebys.com/en/buy/auction/2025/important-watches-part-i-ge2501/daytona-panda-paul-newman-reference-6263-a?locale=en" target="_blank"><u>lot 87</u></a>, is fresh to market, consigned by the family of the original owner, and looks to be in good condition. The serial number fits the range for a Mark 1 dial and is in a known batch of 6263 Newmans — all checks out there. The estimate has been set at CHF 280,000 - 600,000.</p>
  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8e5dfc36-47dc-4ed9-b4cb-a7891db772b4/BAL5.9.25_SBCartier_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Sotheby's.</i></p></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/979d44da-7a90-44c1-a34d-a04a3ff55350/BAL5.9.25_SBOmega_2.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Sotheby's.</i></p></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>Of the 123 other lots at Sotheby's, I'll be watching (pun intended) <a href="https://www.sothebys.com/en/buy/auction/2025/important-watches-part-i-ge2501/tank-allongee-a-yellow-gold-wristwatch-with-eagles?locale=en" target="_blank"><u>lot 53, a Tank Allongée</u></a> with "bec d'aigle", French for "eagle's beak," lugs. The catalog has this one dated to the 1940s, but I would guess it leans more toward 1960. Whatever the year of production, it is a real deal vintage Cartier, produced in collaboration with Edmond Jaeger in Paris, and a rare one at that. Not too many of these "bed d'aigle" Allongées exist. Plus, I like the enameled monograph on the caseback too. Lastly, I'll have my eye on <a href="https://www.sothebys.com/en/buy/auction/2025/important-watches-part-i-ge2501/railmaster-reference-ck-2914-3-a-stainless-steel?locale=en" target="_blank"><u>lot 99, a great-looking Omega Railmaster</u></a>. The vintage Omega market is quite suppressed; someone will get a good watch here and might not pay much for it. See the complete catalog <a href="https://www.sothebys.com/en/buy/auction/2025/important-watches-part-i-ge2501?lotFilter=AllLots" target="_blank"><u>right here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>Christie's — 2007 Patek Philippe Ref. 3970EG-028 With Breguet Numerals And Hands</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A Patek 3970" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ef1b468d-a7f5-43fa-a95e-72c158c43926/BAL5.9.25_CHPatek_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Christie's.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Patek 3970s are all the rage with a certain younger collector who doesn't quite have the affinity for 1518s and 2499s but wants the greatest Patek has to offer. Within this reference, there are many directions one can take, the ultimate level of which is the chase for special order, rare dial configurations. Produced in 2007, after the 3970 was officially retired in 2004, this example, <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/lot/lot-6534074" target="_blank"><u>lot 54</u></a>, is just that, a special order, fitted with a black dial adorned by the ever-collectible Breguet numerals. Any black dial 3970 is rare, but according to Christie's, this is the only known example with a black dial cased in white gold — all begging the question, who was this lucky Patek client? The estimate has been set at CHF 400,000 – 800,000.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="A Breguet pocket watch" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/f18b16c6-eee9-404c-a6fd-7226c8d6a41a/BAL5.9.25_CHBreguet_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Image courtesy of Christie's.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>183 lots fill the rest of the Christie's Geneva catalog this go around, I'll be watching <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/lot/lot-6534130" target="_blank"><u>lot 110, a Breguet pocket watch</u></a> sold initially to Napoleon's sister, La Princesse Pauline Borghese, in 1813 and, importantly, produced during the lifetime of Abraham-Louis Breguet. <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/lot/lot-6534034" target="_blank"><u>Lot 14</u></a> is the first yellow gold Rolex "Le Mans" Daytona, which should be fun. And <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/lot/lot-6534043" target="_blank"><u>lot 23</u></a> looks to be a clean example of Zenith's ref. A386 El Primero could be a great buy at an estimated CHF 5,000 – 10,000. Check out the full catalog <a href="https://www.christies.com/en/auction/rare-watches-featuring-stories-in-time-a-collection-of-exceptional-watches-23915-gnv/" target="_blank"><u>here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>1950s Girard Perregaux Chronograph Ref. 22214 By Universal Genève</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A Girard Perregaux chronograph" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/5ccdea4d-1234-4d6c-8753-cebedff69860/BAL5.9.25_GP_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Away from the big stages of major auction houses, plenty of great watches can still be found. Take this Girard-Perregaux chronograph for example. Made by Universal Genève in the first half of the 1950s, the ref. 22214 is a Girard-Perregaux-specific reference that mimics UG's Compur as a two-register "big eye" chronograph. While the brand is known for many other things today, in the vintage period, Girard-Perregaux marketed Universal Genève-made chronographs such as this one. GP would contract out UG in batches, and the results are watches like this, which tend to have a bit more flair than their UG counterparts — hence, the Breguet numerals.</p>
  	<p>The 35mm "enversteel" stainless steel case is nice and sharp, and while the dial has some flaws to call out, like the staining around the nine o'clock sub-register, we can give it a break for being over 70 years old and less than $4,000, right?</p>
  	<p>An eBay seller out of Stockton, CA, has this listed for a buy it now price of $3,700. The full listing is <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/256148837492" target="_blank"><u>right here</u></a>.</p>
  	<h2>1970s Vacheron Constantin Ref. 7186 in White Gold with Brick Bracelet Retailed by Meister</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="A 1970s Meister-signed Vacheron" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/dac520b8-0319-4ea9-aacf-180f89439675/BAL5.9.25_VC_1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Meister retailer stamps will always make me laugh because I once, in the days of Hodinkee Vintage, put the tagline of "Meister, Meister, read all about it" on a Speedmaster with this retailer stamp. Anyway, this 1970s Vacheron is a lot of watch for the money. It represents an era of the brand where it was conforming to the changing idea of luxury in the 1970s. Integrated bracelets, elegant shapes, and white gold were all the rage. If you pay close attention, VC did a bunch of excellent references in this vein — integrated bracelet watches extend beyond Patek and Piaget!</p>
  	<p>The watch measures a demure yet wearable 22.5mm by 25mm with an elegant 4mm profile. Inside is the caliber 1003, finished to the level one would expect from Vacheron. The Meister stamp indicates that this example was retailed via the esteemed Zurich retailer and, to top it all off, it even has a possibly original, at least period correct, Vacheron box!</p>
  	<p>I found the watch <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/356863000276" target="_blank"><u>via eBay</u></a>, but it comes from a dealer I know and trust in Houston, Texas — Fabsuisse Vintage Watch. The asking price is $8,975, and I'd imagine the team would rather you contact them directly via their website <a href="https://fabsuisse.com/vacheron-constantin-7186-brick-bracelet-retailed-by-meister-1970s/" target="_blank"><u>right here</u></a>.</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d198cae6-6147-4d16-9158-be34038ca3ec/BAL5.9.25_HERO.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Bring a Loupe: The 2025 Geneva Spring Auctions And A Few eBay Gems</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Daniel Roth Extra Plat In Rose Gold (Live Pics &amp; Pricing)</title>
      <dc:creator>Rich Fordon</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 06:00:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/introducing-daniel-roth-extra-plat-rose-gold</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/introducing-daniel-roth-extra-plat-rose-gold</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The brand's second act continues with a warmly-toned reinterpretation of its ultra-thin revival.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/518b13ce-8a05-4ce7-86f0-503067a69581/hero.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	

  	<h3>What We Know</h3>

  	<p>Daniel Roth's revival began with the yellow gold <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/its-here-daniel-roth-has-been-revived-with-the-new-tourbillon-souscription" target="_blank"><u>Tourbillon Souscription</u></a>, a quiet, confident, and very La Fabrique du Temps Louis Vuitton-powered reentry into the world of extremely high watchmaking. That watch was sold via a <i>souscription </i>model, produced in a limited run of 20 pieces, and served as both a nod to the past and a technical statement of intent. That March 2023 release was followed by the <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/intro-daniel-roth-tourbillon-in-rose-gold" target="_blank"><u>rose gold Tourbillon</u></a> in August of 2024, this being a "standard" version that was limited by production. Roth has rolled out the same playbook with the Extra Plat. The <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/intro-daniel-roth-extra-plat-souscription" target="_blank"><u>yellow gold Souscription</u></a> version hit in January of this year, and now, roughly three months later, we have the rose gold follow-up.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/fac1a1d8-1daa-4e52-b4a7-ac9ca3933026/L1100615.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The second watch in the second model line from the Roth redux, the Extra Plat in rose gold, has officially arrived. Now rendered in 5N rose gold and with roughly the same design, this "standard" Extra Plat will be made available through select retailers instead of the souscription model.</p>
  	<p>The silhouette remains the same — a 38.6mm by 35.5mm double ellipse case, a mere 7.7mm thick — and still unmistakably Daniel Roth. What changes is the tone and texture: the warmth of the 5N alloy softens the already elegant lines, while the new production strategy signals a gradual expansion of the brand's presence. Also appealing to a wider audience is the now-open caseback. Sure, the original Roth referencing closed casebacks of both Souscription models are like catnip to "true enthusiasts," but in 2025, if you're going to put real effort into movement finishing, I do want to flip the watch over and have a look for myself.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold movement" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/7563212d-c055-4658-a3ea-a94726f7af1f/L1100656.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/671128ca-d938-4969-8eed-5764216cc9d8/L1100616.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/b912c4c2-d8c5-4767-b44c-56faf22ffb1f/L1100652.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>Upon flipping the latest Extra Plat over, we're greeted with the same caliber DR002 introduced last year — a manually-wound movement designed and finished under the guidance of master watchmakers Michel Navas and Enrico Barbasini at La Fabrique du Temps Louis Vuitton. Built specifically for the Extra Plat and this double-ellipse case, the DR002 is everything we have come to expect from Roth. As for finishing, it's quite evident even in photos that the rounded, polished anglage and sharp corners are only possible via handcraft. The Roth team put extra focus on the tactile feel of the winding click here. Having experienced the watch in person, I can say this effort was well worth it — the Extra Plat is a pleasure to wind.</p>
  	<p>The dial of the new Extra Plat Rose Gold is a real standout, even compared to the previous Extra Plat Souscription. Now quietly two-tone, it is produced in two parts and features hand-done guilloché. The base is a solid disc of white gold, meticulously hand-decorated with linear guilloché — a technique known as <i>guillochage en ligne</i> — that lends texture and calls back to vintage Roths. A 5N rose gold chapter ring encircles the dial, framing black Roman numerals. The hands, rendered in black-coated stainless steel, provide crisp contrast without resorting to lume. It's an overall layered and brilliantly executed look.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/e522ea68-f3ce-4b8e-b793-e8c2ba6b7513/L1100651.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold is a part of the brand's, again, "standard" catalog. Production is not explicitly limited, and the price is CHF 49,000.</p>
  	<h3>What We Think</h3>

  	<p>The revival of Daniel Roth was frankly easy to be skeptical of when LVMH first <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/daniel-roth-to-relaunch-in-2023-with-help-from-la-fabrique-du-temps" target="_blank">announced the news</a><a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/daniel-roth-to-relaunch-in-2023-with-help-from-la-fabrique-du-temps" target="_blank"><u> in September of 2023</u></a>. I was among that group, to be fair. As a fan of the vintage (or neo-vintage) Daniel Roth offerings, I wondered how a LVMH-fueled revival would fare in the mid-2020s. My preconceived notions have since turned into excitement. The more time I spend around the products coming out of La Fabrique du Temps, the more I am impressed.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold on the wrist" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d8f851fe-54d5-4c64-b80e-7a6f2e16b234/L1100658.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ea520c8e-5661-460d-a850-f565b2130bdb/L1100687.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8b87e603-f26d-4841-8d14-98833cc2427c/L1100637.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>Throughout, the details are just absolutely nailed. Yes, the core takeaway from this article is that there is a change in case material and subtle tweaks here and there. And yes, the rose and grey tones create a gorgeous product. However, the Extra Plat Rose Gold is also a continuation of Daniel Roth as a brand and a step toward building a serious catalog of offerings.</p>
  	<p>This is all intentional. It's the same way Daniel Roth was built the first time around, starting in 1989 and through the early 1990s. Tourbillon in 1989, Extra Plat in 1990, then a Perpetual Calendar in 1991. It's also the same way most independent watchmakers of this century have built; slowly, in a meticulous manner to get all the details right. When making watches at this level, you can't throw a full catalog at the market in the first year. It just doesn't make sense.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold movement" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/0a7e263e-a681-44b6-a9e2-1d3665cb6912/L1100636.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2142a654-d920-429a-8a2f-1151585daa90/L1100627.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/610c6bc0-e82b-46ac-98d7-e9cbe68ccc7b/L1100613.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>But what are those details? Seeing the watch in person is the best way to appreciate what the new Roth is up to, but via photos, one can still appreciate the slightly reinterpreted case, where the midcase sits equally as far from the top as it does the bottom. This is a change from the vintage Extra Plat, where the top portion slightly outweighs the caseback. The change in the guilloché pattern is nailed, too. Roth used Clou de Paris (like on the Souscription version), but the vast majority of 1990s Extra Plat examples feature a straight pattern like the guillochage en ligne of this rose gold version. Decisions and references like this are easy to get wrong, but not here, not with Roth.</p>
  	<h2>The Basics</h2>

  	<p><strong>Brand:</strong> Daniel Roth<br><strong>Model:</strong> Extra Plat Rose Gold<br><strong>Reference Number: </strong>DBBD01A1</p>

<p><strong>Case Dimensions:</strong> 38.6mm (length), 35.5mm (width)<br><strong>Thickness:</strong> 7.7mm<br><strong>Case Material:</strong> 5H rose gold<br><strong>Dial Color:</strong> Solid white gold base with linear guilloché, 5N rose gold chapter ring<br><strong>Indexes:</strong> Black Roman numerals<br><strong>Lume:</strong> None<br><strong>Water Resistance:</strong> 30 meters<br><strong>Strap/Bracelet: </strong>Calfskin leather strap, 20mm lug width</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Daniel Roth Extra Plat Rose Gold" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/15b9646f-18d0-4e8a-b80e-d617d0630e9b/L1100702.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<h2>The Movement</h2>

  	<p><strong>Caliber:</strong> DR002<br><strong>Functions:</strong> Hours and minutes<br><strong>Power Reserve:</strong> 65 hours<br><strong>Winding:</strong> Manual<br><strong>Frequency:</strong> 4 Hz<br><strong>Jewels:</strong> 21<br><strong>Chronometer Certified:</strong> No<br><strong>Additional Details: </strong>Manufacture manual winding developed and assembled at La Fabrique du Temps Louis Vuitton under the supervision of Michel Navas and Enrico Barbasini</p>
  	<h2>Pricing & Availability</h2>

  	<p><strong>Price:</strong> CHF 49,000<br><strong>Availability:</strong> Now<br><strong>Limited Edition: </strong>No</p>

<p>For more, <a href="https://www.danielroth.com/" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/518b13ce-8a05-4ce7-86f0-503067a69581/hero.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Introducing: The Daniel Roth Extra Plat In Rose Gold (Live Pics &amp; Pricing)</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Celebrates 55 Years of Titanium Innovation</title>
      <dc:creator>Tim Jeffreys</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/citizen-celebrates-55-years-of-titanium-innovation</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/citizen-celebrates-55-years-of-titanium-innovation</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>A look back at Citizen's class-leading work with titanium and the launch of the brand's latest innovation - Duratect Amber Yellow. </p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/89605e0e-1b1d-453b-a3ec-187dfa60d252/citizen-ti-hero.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	

  	<p>In a world of endless options and endless designs, it's genuinely appreciated whenever a brand narrows its aperture and demonstrates a steadfast focus on mastering a medium. I was reminded of this last week while looking at a rock. Well, it's more than just any rock, as it turns out, it's actual titanium sponge foraged from the ground. I was at an event for Citizen, the brand that introduced the first titanium watch to the market fifty-five years ago and continues to innovate in watchmaking with this remarkable material. The rock could have easily been confused with an <i>objet d'art</i> (we were in a Chelsea gallery, after all), but instead, it forms the basis for an entire line of watches and has become synonymous with the brand.</p>

<p>To celebrate the fifty-fifth anniversary, Citizen organized an engaging and informative exhibition called "Super Titanium: The Beauty of Time." Titanium, as I would soon discover in much greater detail, is far more than just a rock.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Titanium" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/7e6da654-5141-4072-9be5-ef130ca4f2f9/L1010015.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A titanium sponge.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<h2>The History: Pioneering Titanium in Watchmaking</h2>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d3efe6da-670c-4910-8968-52ee5a544a85/x8.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Citizen X-8 Chronometer.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Citizen revolutionized the watchmaking industry in 1970 with the launch of the X-8 Chronometer, the world's first titanium watch. The name X-8 carries a special meaning – X represents the unknown, while 8 represents the infinity symbol (∞), conveying the endless possibilities of titanium. </p>

<p>Recognizing titanium's immense potential long before it became a watchmaking staple, Citizen was among the first to harness its exceptional corrosion resistance and lightweight properties, qualities previously reserved for aerospace and medical applications. Despite titanium's early challenges, such as difficulty in machining and polishing, Citizen persevered, refining their expertise and developing advanced surface-hardening treatments.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="attesa" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/e9307c21-1a26-470d-ad0f-959e55b93173/attesa.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Citizen ATTESA.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The brand continued to innovate throughout the decades. In 1987, Citizen launched the first ATTESA model, which utilized new processing technology to give titanium a soft metallic glow. This resulted in an elegant business watch – a departure from the rough, matte finish standard for titanium watches at the time. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="aspec" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ce050172-ccff-4fd1-bb79-3073e37903df/aspec.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Citizen ASPEC World Time.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The year 2000 marked the beginning of the Super Titanium era with the ASPEC World Time, the first model to feature Super Titanium treated with Duratect, Citizen's proprietary surface hardening technology. This innovation culminated in the creation of Super Titanium, a next-generation material strengthened with Duratect technology, setting new industry standards in resilience. Super Titanium delivers exceptional scratch resistance and all-day comfort as a material that is five times harder and 40% lighter than stainless steel.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="ecodrive" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/47056a3a-d390-4f43-b9c6-678db132af41/promaster.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Citizen Promaster Eco-Drive.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Citizen continued pushing boundaries with the 2006 Promaster Eco-Drive radio-controlled watch, introducing Duratect MRK+DLC double surface hardening technology. In 2016, they launched the delicate Duratect Sakura pink, inspired by cherry blossoms, and in 2018, the Ultra-thin Eco-Drive One with an incredible thickness of just 3.53 mm. The brand's commitment to innovation continued with gold-colored Duratect MRK in 2019, Recrystallized Titanium in 2022, and the unique Duratect DLC Blue the same year, which brings us to today.</p>
  	<h2>Modern Day Developments In Titanium</h2>

  	<p>It's one thing to make titanium watches and to make the movements that power them, and Citizen has that covered, but did you know that Citizen also manufactures the machines that craft the watches from titanium? Their dedication to working with this special material includes leading the industry in figuring out <i>how </i>to use titanium in modern watchmaking. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Titanium, in a different form." src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/71817414-aad9-4ef4-96be-9a1bf412a28a/titanium_SocialMedia.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Titanium, in a different form.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>To learn more about it, I had the opportunity to sit down with Mr. Kazuma Sato, who traveled from Japan for the event. As an expert in the field responsible for developing the new colorways for Super Titanium, he shared insights into his creative process. A fan of antiques and vintage aesthetics, he aimed to create a color that wasn't gaudy or flashy —a goal he and his team certainly achieved, letting functionality inform design, not the other way around.</p>
  	<p>Throughout the exhibition and conversations with Mr. Sato, I learned about the development of titanium through Citizen's history and specifically about the creation of Duratect Amber Yellow. The exhibition displayed about 40 titanium samples used to define the exact color of the watch. All of them looked identical to the naked eye. A microscope invited closer inspection, revealing subtle differences between samples. Even more astonishing was how, under just 4x magnification, the untreated titanium appeared scratched and imperfect, while to the naked eye, it seemed smooth.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/4a12d37e-34d9-42d1-bbaa-eb00d5ccd310/Cleaning1_SocialMedia.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Titanium cases being cleaned.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<h2>The Duratect Amber Yellow</h2>

  	<p>Citizen's latest innovation is Duratect Amber Yellow, a warm yet understated golden hue that complements all skin tones, suits any occasion, and embodies a sophisticated aesthetic for the modern wearer who values both style and substance. At the core of this innovation is Citizen's Duratect surface-hardening technology, which enhances the hardness and color of the metal through multiple coatings applied to the base titanium. The brand's manufacturing process was meticulously refined to create the most enduring shade that sets itself apart from conventional gold colors, offering a distinctive and versatile look.</p>
  	<p>Duratect Amber Yellow is created using a niobium-titanium alloy, eliminating nickel content and ensuring hypoallergenic properties. This makes it the ideal choice for individuals with sensitivities to metals such as nickel, cobalt, and chromium, which, as I was told, is up to 15% of folks. The first use of this material was for Citizen's recently announced Amber Yellow xC watch, as shown below. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/781d5ea0-9b61-46f6-82dd-67e7288ec17e/c3.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/21954b4d-045e-4b8c-b72d-156013a2a8c6/c2.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/3dd75716-1de8-4568-82a5-da150d53ac40/c4.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<p>We can't speak about titanium without referring to its hardness, and measuring approximately 1,700-2,300 HV, Duratect Amber Yellow is 10 to 20 times harder than traditional gold plating and significantly more resistant to scratches, making it one of the highest levels of hardness within Citizen's Duratect lineup. Beyond its resilience, this unique colorway, made by mixing various gases with titanium, was developed with a focus on functionality and universal appeal.</p>
  	<p>Named for its resemblance to natural amber—the fossilized resin of ancient trees—Duratect Amber Yellow mirrors the qualities of its namesake: gentle on the skin, exceptionally durable, and rich in visual depth. Just as natural amber has been cherished for generations, Citizen envisions timepieces featuring Duratect Amber Yellow as long-lasting symbols of style and craftsmanship, adding to the current color lineup, including Silver, Gold, Black, Blue, Pink, and Sakura pink.</p>

<p>This xC comes in at 27 mm in diameter and 8.2 mm thick. Powered by a Photoelectric Eco-Drive movement and, of course, in the Duratect Super-Titanium, this model is currently available in Japan. <a href="https://citizen.jp/shop/xc/g/gES9492-57D/" target="_blank">You can see it here</a><a href="https://citizen.jp/shop/xc/g/gES9492-57D/" target="_blank">,</a> and it will be available in very limited quantities at the Citizen Flagship store in Manhattan later this summer.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Citizen Attesa Hakuto-R" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/c085f7ac-314a-4cc9-a052-bda5a795e943/attesamodern_.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Titanium in it's final form—Citizen Attesa Hakuto-R.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>All of these alloys and special processes bring me back to the rock. I'm no geologist, but I would venture to guess that raw titanium hasn't changed much since it was unearthed for the first time. As titanium continues to grow in popularity and application, Citizen continues to lead the charge in finding ways to advance materials science with the goal of making a more comfortable, more broadly accessible, lightweight, and hard-wearing watch.</p>

<p>For more, <a href="https://www.citizenwatch.com/us/en/" target="_blank">visit Citizen's website.</a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/89605e0e-1b1d-453b-a3ec-187dfa60d252/citizen-ti-hero.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Citizen Celebrates 55 Years of Titanium Innovation</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happenings: Dubai Watch Week Is Back This November With Over 90 Brands In Attendance</title>
      <dc:creator>Mark Kauzlarich</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/happenings-dubai-watch-week-2025</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/happenings-dubai-watch-week-2025</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>One of the premiere events of the watch calendar returns for its 7th time, now bigger than ever.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/42a3e086-cfcd-432e-b18b-92325002dbf4/20231118_DubaiWatchWeek_1081.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	<p>Every two years, the watch world converges on Dubai for one of the highlight events of the watch calendar: Dubai Watch Week, brought to you by Ahmed Seddiqi, the UAE's premier retailer, which is celebrating its 75th anniversary this year. That's right, the retailer Ahmed Seddiqi is older than the UAE itself. To celebrate, the 7th edition of Dubai Watch Week will be bigger than ever, with 90 participating brands joining the 2025 edition.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Dubai Watch Week" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ee086cf7-0ebf-4a06-9702-68fd381254ac/L1002220.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Dubai Watch Week runs from November 19 to 23, 2025, at a brand new location, Dubai Mall, Burj Park. The new venue spans over 200,000 square feet in the heart of Dubai, housing brand booths, programming, immersive experiences, and activations, plus the chance to see hundreds of watches from those 90 brands. It's also a great place to go watch spotting – which James Stacey and I did in 2023, <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/photo-report-dubai-watch-week" target="_blank">when 23,000 visitors came to the event.</a> You can also walk down the hallways of the event to escape the heat and run into Philippe Dufour, Kari Voutilainen, and Rexhep Rexhepi, all within about 10 feet – not something that you can really do many other places in the world.</p>
  	<p>The top participating brands include Rolex, Audemars Piguet, Tudor, Van Cleef &amp; Arpels, Hublot, Chopard, Ferdinand Berthoud, Breitling, Girard-Perregaux, Bulgari, TAG Heuer, Chanel and Gerald Charles, all with their own standalone booths, but there are now 46% more brands than last year helping round out the event. The full list is below.</p>
  	  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/93d36727-f6ea-4609-84c2-af0d16751fbd/L1002277.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>
  <figure>
    <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1ea1b535-9868-4239-b4d1-6371b0cc97e2/20231118_DubaiWatchWeek_036_2200px.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
    <figcaption></figcaption>
  </figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Dubai Edition Day Date" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ecb96b56-a973-40b2-858e-c20870fd220b/20231116_DubaiWatchWeek_018_2200px.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The best part? Dubai Watch Week is free and open to the public, so if you can get to Dubai, there's no reason not to attend. To see the full list of participating brands and to register for the event, you can <a href="https://www.dubaiwatchweek.com/register?utm_source=prparternships&amp;utm_medium=press_release&amp;utm_campaign=dww_may&amp;utm_content=dww25_brands" target="_blank">visit Dubai Watch Week's website.</a></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/42a3e086-cfcd-432e-b18b-92325002dbf4/20231118_DubaiWatchWeek_1081.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Happenings: Dubai Watch Week Is Back This November With Over 90 Brands In Attendance</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HSNY Expands Educational Offerings with New Academic Programming</title>
      <dc:creator>Carolina  Navarro</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:00:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/hsny-expands-educational-offerings-with-new-academic-programming</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/hsny-expands-educational-offerings-with-new-academic-programming</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Beginning May 20, 2025!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/49805932-caaa-4889-a721-ea67d8fe262c/httpscdn.evbuc.comimages10184193.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	<p>The <a href="https://hs-ny.org/" target="_blank"><u>Horological Society of New York</u></a> (HSNY), America's oldest watchmaking guild, founded in 1866, announces today an expansion of its educational initiatives with the launch of new academic programming set to begin this spring. Building on its 159-year legacy of advancing the art and science of horology, HSNY is introducing a suite of courses and learning opportunities designed to meet the growing demand for comprehensive horological education.</p>

<p>The new academic offerings will include structured six-week courses led by accredited New York City professors and will be offered to students ages 18 and up. Courses are tailored for enthusiasts and no prior experience is required to enroll.</p>

<p>"Our goal is to make horological education more accessible and relevant for today's world," said Nicholas Manousos, Executive Director of HSNY. "Our new academic programming offers a unique educational experience grounded in tradition but looking to the future."</p>
  	<h3>COURSE 1: America at Night (Tuesdays from May 20 — June 24)</h3>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2e2c95f2-2030-4f97-896b-aeb5c7741ad0/Course1-DanielWilkHeadshot.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>What makes night different today? Americans pioneered technologies of illumination, business models that keep us up late, cultures and subcultures that populate the night, social and psychological problems of night owls, and some of the solutions to those problems. This class will examine the history of these developments and give students a chance to talk about paintings, stories, and songs that celebrate and lament being awake at night.</p>

<p>Taught by Daniel Levinson Wilk</p>

<p>Cost: $150, Capacity: 11</p>

<p><i>Daniel Levinson Wilk is Professor of American History at SUNY-Fashion Institute of Technology. He writes about the history of waiters, elevators, and the modern service sector, and serves on the board of the Remember the Triangle Fire Coalition. He is currently writing a book called How To Tip With Style.</i></p>
  	<h3>COURSE 2: Time: The Big Questions (Wednesdays from May 21 — June 25) </h3>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6d7d7295-2156-4a2f-a49a-7bd0379b8171/Course2-JeffFeddersenHeadshotA.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Time is at once fundamental and mysterious. From the 2000-year-old Antikythera Mechanism to modern cesium-fountain clocks, humans have long sought to understand temporal patterns in nature, and build mechanisms to measure, reflect and predict those patterns. We're at a unique moment, one in which we've developed the ability to perceive relativistic effects on time at the smallest scales, while struggling to think and plan across generations.</p>

<p>In this discussion course, students will reflect on the deep mysteries of time. How can we locate our place in the vast history and expanse of the Universe? Why do the planets, moon, and stars move the way they do? What does the future hold? Does time even exist? The course will draw from the rich materials available at the HSNY's Jost Bürgi Research Library, and from the instructor's graduate course at NYU, "Time".</p>

<p>Taught by Jeffrey Feddersen</p>

<p>Time: 6:00PM  — 7:30PM</p>

<p>Cost: $150, Capacity: 11</p>

<p><i>Jeffrey Feddersen has collaborated for over two decades with artists, musicians, designers, and engineers to make amazing things. Trained in computer science and music, his code and creativity can be found in projects for groups ranging from the Hayden Planetarium to HBO. He is a dedicated teacher and has held research and fellowship positions at NYU's digital arts graduate program, ITP, where he is currently a Production Mentor. At ITP he developed the video curriculum supporting creative electronics, and founded the courses "Energy" and "Time". The Time course combines physics and philosophy to trace the connections between time-keeping, computation, and human attempts to understand the universe.</i></p>
  	<p>Classes will be held at HSNY's Jost Bürgi Research Library located at 20 West 44th Street, Suite 501, New York, NY 10036.</p>

<p>Enrollment for spring programming opens on April 28, 2025. For more information about the new academic programming and to register, visit<a href="http://www.hs-ny.org/"> </a><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/o/horological-society-of-new-york-8304492355" target="_blank">Eventbrite</a>.</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/49805932-caaa-4889-a721-ea67d8fe262c/httpscdn.evbuc.comimages10184193.png?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">HSNY Expands Educational Offerings with New Academic Programming</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: Richard Mille Quietly Dropped A New Limited Release With Ferrari's Formula 1 Driver – The RM72-01 'Charles LeClerc'</title>
      <dc:creator>Mark Kauzlarich</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/introducing-richard-mille-72-01-charles-leclerc</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/introducing-richard-mille-72-01-charles-leclerc</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The long-time friend of Richard Mille has been wearing the watch for weeks, but only a few people have noticed – now we have all the details.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a8c1660c-4838-4b25-9b8d-a198835d39b5/Hero_GettyImages-2209864016.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	

  	<h3>What We Know</h3>

  	<p>Fresh off a thrilling race weekend at the Miami Grand Prix, we've got more Formula 1 news with the surprise discovery that Richard Mille quietly launched a new model with a long-time friend of the brand (read: ambassador) and Ferrari driver Charles Leclerc. The new RM72-01 "Charles Leclerc" edition takes the brand's automatic flyback chronograph platform and adds a number of tweaks for the beloved Monégasque F1 driver.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Charles LeClerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/c52fd466-0f46-4a07-ab54-ff94ca4acbce/2200px_GettyImages-2213395782.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Charles LeClerc and Carlos Sainz leaving the paddock in Miami. <i>Photo credit Kym Illman/Getty Images</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The most obvious design change here is the use of a white quartz TPT case with red stripes and caseband that is a nod to the Monegasque flag. The skeletonized chronograph display ditches any numerals for the hours while sticking to that same red and white theme for the running seconds and chronograph counters. The black crown resembles a tire twisting under the torque of a car's acceleration, and the date window is also framed in red and white.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="RM72-01 Charles Leclerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a8419205-c019-4c62-a549-924bbbd3552e/rm_72_01_3_4_front_wb.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="RM72-01 Charles Leclerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ff880b2c-194d-4507-a6a1-c2619f253263/rm_72_01_3_h_wb.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The watch is powered by Richard Mille's caliber CRMC-1, a flyback chronograph with 30-minute and 24-hour totalizers, running seconds, and a column-wheel control system and double tilting pinion clutch system. The movement also features a function indicator to show the position of the crown (winding, setting, or date adjustment) and semi-instantaneous date.  The watch runs at 28,800 vph with a cupro-beryllium (CuBe) freesprung adjustable mass balance, fast-rotating mainspring barrel, and has a 50-hour power reserve. The automatic winding system uses a platinum rotor running on ceramic bearings.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="RM72-01 Charles Leclerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/0ce2dd96-1d57-4b78-916b-7261461bda94/rm_72_01_3_4_back_wb.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The watch is a limited edition of only 150 pieces that's already being delivered to customers. The retail price is $330,000, but if the equally limited <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/richard-mille-rm-72-01-le-mans-classic" target="_blank">RM72-01 LeMans Classic</a> is any sign of how things go, the eventual prices on the secondary market will get a bit bonkers.</p>
  	<h3>What We Think</h3>

  	<p>Story time: This is my first-ever dog-powered watch spotting. While a lot of brands do everything they can to leverage Formula 1 and their ambassadors to launch a watch, Richard Mille didn’t say a thing about this release. Instead, I was sent <a href="https://www.instagram.com/share/BAn1ZGYfgp" target="_blank">an adorable video of the ever-excited star of F1, Leo Leclerc</a> (Charles Leclerc’s adorable dachshund), playing with Charles after the Miami Grand Prix. I recognized that the watch that Charles was wearing wasn’t something I’d seen before – it was close to Bubba Watson’s pink and white quartz case, but very obviously an RM72-01. Then I looked back at his Instagram, past my preferred content (dogs, dogs, and more dogs), and saw that he's been wearing this watch for a while.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="RM72-01 Charles Leclerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/95eff139-d353-4ce3-b44e-981b8f9912ad/2200px_GettyImages-2213370206.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p><i>Photo credit Hector Vivas/Getty Images.</i></p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<center><blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DJCSfhCMCxt/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DJCSfhCMCxt/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div></div></div><div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewBox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div><div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div></div><div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"><div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div></div><div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div></div><div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div></div></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div></div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DJCSfhCMCxt/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Charles Leclerc (@charles_leclerc)</a></p></div></blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script></center>

  	<p>That prompted me to do some Googling, and the only information I could find (as of early Tuesday) was <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DId6Qv5yXfT/" target="_blank">a post from a dealer in Dubai</a> who had a picture of the watch in hand – despite the fact that Charles has been wearing this watch since the Bahrain GP – and seemingly no one noticed. That all but confirmed that the watch wasn't just a prototype, but a product for sale. Luckily, I was able to get the official details from Richard Mille directly, and now we have the info on the RM72-01 "Leo Leclerc" – I mean... "Charles Leclerc" Edition. And my take? I really like it – maybe not for me, but definitely for Leclerc.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="RM72-01 Charles Leclerc" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/15670065-4bc2-4297-8210-f8dfc8ceab60/rm_72_01_6_h_wb.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>There's no use litigating a price of a Richard Mille – these are hyper limited, extremely exclusive, and fantastically expensive watches, and that's the point. They are often extremely loud as well, so why not lean into that the way that Richard Mille has for one of their closest friends? Yes, this has a little bit of “peppermint candy cane" vibes, but who cares? Sure, I would personally always go for a more low-key option like an RM67-02 in black, but for the Monegasque Ferrari driver, this watch is perfect.</p>
  	<h2>The Basics</h2>

  	<p><strong>Brand:</strong> Richard Mille<br><strong>Model:</strong> RM72-01 'Charles Leclerc'</p>

<p><strong>Diameter:</strong> 38.4mm (wide) by 47.34mm (end to end)<br><strong>Thickness:</strong> 11.68mm<br><strong>Case Material:</strong> White quartz TPT with red accents and stripes<br><strong>Dial Color:</strong> Skeletonized<br><strong>Indexes:</strong> Tachymeter rehaut and printed display<br><strong>Lume:</strong> On hands and indices<br><strong>Water Resistance:</strong> 30 meters<br><strong>Strap/Bracelet: </strong>Rubber strap</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Richard Mille" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1ae8a0e6-940e-4e03-a56f-d91cc070a125/rm_72_01_5_h_wb.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<h2>The Movement</h2>

  	<p><strong>Caliber:</strong> RM Caliber CRMC-1<br><strong>Functions:</strong> Hours, minutes, seconds, date, and flyback chronograph with 60-minute and 24-hour counter <br><strong>Diameter:</strong> 29.10 by 31.25 mm<br><strong>Thickness:</strong> 6.05mm<br><strong>Power Reserve:</strong> 50 hours<br><strong>Winding:</strong> Automatic<br><strong>Frequency:</strong> 28,800 vph<br><strong>Jewels:</strong> 39<br><strong>Chronometer Certified:</strong> No<br><strong>Additional Details: </strong>Micro-blasted and hand-chamfered movement; CuBe balance (4 arms, 4 setting weights, moment of inertia 7.5 mg•cm2 , angle of lift 50°); Shock protection from transparent INCABLOC 908.22.211.100 system</p>
  	<h2>Pricing & Availability</h2>

  	<p><strong>Price:</strong> $330,000<br><strong>Availability:</strong> Immediately<br><strong>Limited Edition: </strong>Yes, 150 pieces</p>

<p>For more, click <a href="https://www.richardmille.com/collections/rm-72-01-automatic-flyback-chronograph" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
  	<p><i>Lead photo credit Mark Thompson/Getty Images.</i></p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a8c1660c-4838-4b25-9b8d-a198835d39b5/Hero_GettyImages-2209864016.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Introducing: Richard Mille Quietly Dropped A New Limited Release With Ferrari's Formula 1 Driver – The RM72-01 'Charles LeClerc'</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo Report: Watch (And Camera) Spotting At Leica’s Centennial Celebration In NYC</title>
      <dc:creator>Troy Barmore</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:02:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/leica-celebrates-100-years-of-the-leica-i-with-new-york-auction-preview-we-captured-all-the-cameras</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/leica-celebrates-100-years-of-the-leica-i-with-new-york-auction-preview-we-captured-all-the-cameras</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This event had it all—Jason Momoa, one of the first Leica Cameras ever created, and some seriously solid watch spotting.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1bd78581-6642-46cd-9cc2-2bb41d3900f8/leica-header.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	

  	<p>If one were to make a Venn diagram showing the overlap of Leica camera lovers and watch enthusiasts, it would almost be a perfect circle. This past weekend, the iconic German camera manufacturer hosted an all-out block party in front of their flagship boutique in NYC's Meatpacking District. It was a convergence of enthusiasm for camera lovers and photography aficionados. The occasion? The celebration of 100 years of continuous camera manufacturing.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica 0" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/852d512f-135f-4ced-a2c4-7c43ae8bc704/IMG_6645.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica 0-Serie no.112 circa 1923</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The multi-day event began with a presentation for the press and friends of the brand. Leica saviors, Owner Dr. Andreas Kaufmann and Karin Rehn-Kaufmann, were joined by the likes of legendary photographer Ralph Gibson as well as other Leica executives, to reflect on the legacy of Leica's century of building some of the most important cameras in history. To punctuate that legacy, Leica prepared an exhibition of a selection of photographs from their archives. Additionally, lots from the upcoming Leitz Photographica Auction were on display, including Leica 0-Serie no. 112, the prototype camera that was delivered to Oskar Barnack himself.</p>
  	<p>This rare prototype, assembled in 1923 and personally accepted by Oskar Barnack (the inventor of the Leica small format camera), will headline the upcoming auction on June 27th at Leica Welt in Wetzlar, Germany. Other notable cameras on display include the 100th Leica serially produced—a Leica I Mod. A (Anastigmat), which was delivered to British advertising and marketing agency Ogilvy in 1925 and was the first Leica to arrive in the United Kingdom; and a Leica M3 with serial number 700,000 that was gifted to renowned sports photographer and skiing pioneer Stefan Kruckenhauser and is the first serial number of all M cameras. "The vintage camera auction hosted by Leica is the largest in the world and has been attracting collectors and investors for years," says Alexander Sedlak, Managing Director of Leitz Photographica Auction.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica team" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/bd3764a6-f4bf-4907-a8c2-7a7d8acad831/IMG_6492.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Left to right - President of Leica North America Mike Giannasttasio, CEO of Leica Camera AG Matthias Harsch, Owner of Leica AG Dr. Andreas Kaufmann, Art Director &amp; Chief Representative of Leica Galleries Karin Rehn-Kaufmann</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>The auction preview coincides with the "<a href="https://leica-camera.com/en-US/photography/100-years-exhibitions/in-conversation-sara-messinger-bruce-davidson" target="_blank">100 Years of Leica" exhibition by Bruce Davidson and Sara Messinger from May 1st to June 15th</a>. The Pop-Up Gallery will additionally showcase 100 historical images curated by Karin-Rehn Kaufmann, Art Director of Leica Galleries International. This celebration highlights Leica's enduring legacy as a premium camera manufacturer with over 150 years of history and continued commitment to photographic excellence and innovation.</p>
  	<p>Following the presentation, the doors of the exhibition and Leica's flagship were opened, while the street in between was closed, to make way for thousands of guests to descend with cameras in hand (as well as quite a number of killer watches on wrists). The festivities culminated Saturday evening with a private concert by Leica lover Jason Momoa's band ÖOF TATATÁ at the Whitney Museum.</p>
  	<p>Scroll through for some images from the events, and if you're in NYC over the next couple of weeks, be sure to stop by the exhibition.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Andreas Kaufmann" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/c37d35df-c37c-434c-9f8d-372c0a7ee40a/IMG_6513.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Dr. Andreas Kaufmann gives remarks, a red prototype Leica APO lens on his M camera.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Karin Rehn Kaufmann and Photographer Ralph Gibson " src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/e6bfbfd7-b83a-46c6-8bd4-ad85a097c607/IMG_6573.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Karin Rehn Kaufmann and photographer Ralph Gibson (wearing a Rolex Submariner ref. 5512).</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Richard Mille RM 30-01" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/87a8f777-2b74-4b48-8518-5ae92bb2e8b7/IMG_6596.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Richard Mille RM 30-01.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica ZM 12 Steel Blue Orange worn by Karin Rehn-Kaufmann" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/e1518814-7d7c-4259-80e8-38c40f7372bc/IMG_6601.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica ZM 12 Steel Blue Orange worn by Karin Rehn-Kaufmann.</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica ZM 2 on the wrist of Dr. Andreas Kaufmann" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/55a155f6-66ad-41f2-8bd4-8a916a2bf573/IMG_6613.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica ZM 2 on the wrist of Dr. Andreas Kaufmann.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Selections from Leica&#39;s archive for the 100-Year Exhibition" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a6c568f9-bc7d-4561-8717-482d86532211/IMG_6629.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Selections from Leica's archive for the 100-Year Exhibition.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica MP &#39;Leitz Park&#39; by King Nerd" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1465e2e7-dc36-4289-b82f-f9610ad69feb/IMG_6637.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica MP 'Leitz Park' by King Nerd.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Habring² Felix Copper" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/bf48d891-4546-4fd0-b782-c8f32b6e9669/IMG_6642.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Habring² Felix Copper.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica 0-Serie no.112 circa 1923" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6a2c6fe3-d1a3-46d2-bf82-f66a822b5e51/IMG_6652.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica 0-Serie no.112 circa 1923.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a watch" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/f8e3be56-e85e-44aa-b7a8-48e820ebfa54/IMG_6666.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Tag Heuer Diver" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/3fffac7d-7b7a-4463-874b-3b4994b82f13/IMG_6670.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Tag Heuer diver.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Filmmaker Roberto Monticello, aka the &#39;Mayer of Meatpacking&#39;" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/5352cbe2-2576-42cd-8cd5-a111b84018db/IMG_6673.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Filmmaker Roberto Monticello, aka the 'Mayer of Meatpacking'.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Seiko 5 SNK803" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/89e08e68-7b86-4d28-8fa2-fade88126473/IMG_6696.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Seiko 5 SNK803.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Omega Speedmaster Calibre 321" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/09eebc85-3bf7-457a-a628-bfc376cc701b/IMG_6699.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Omega Speedmaster Calibre 321.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Limited Edition Leica M11 100 Years of Leica &quot;NEW YORK USA&quot;" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/aaa39eb9-e3cb-433b-b5dd-9d8ebacf571d/IMG_6701.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Limited Edition Leica M11 100 Years of Leica "NEW YORK USA".&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="The Leica Flagship boutique in Meatpacking, packed to capacity" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/44e2ad7b-ed09-485d-9093-1143e531cb87/IMG_6702.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>The Leica Flagship boutique in Meatpacking, packed to capacity.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Panerai Luminor PAM00423 3 Day Power Reserve &amp; Leica M10-P Safari" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/5e9ef462-7cc8-47a1-8715-f0fc5774a0ab/IMG_6715.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Panerai Luminor PAM00423 3 Day Power Reserve &amp; Leica M10-P Safari.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica ZM 12 Steel Silver Grey" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/39bf8389-4756-4371-b230-b1294c903b75/IMG_6726.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Leica ZM 12 Steel Silver Grey.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Baltic MR Classic Salmon on BOR Bracelet" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/f7022103-3e73-4e24-bbf1-fb0bb93e9a69/IMG_6731.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Baltic MR Classic Salmon on BOR Bracelet.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a photographer" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8f8fdf1c-3c22-430b-bcea-214caba85e55/IMG_6732.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="2 Ladies Tone Omega Constellation" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/0353abfe-d629-433a-a632-2e7cb07c8e6d/IMG_6740.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Ladies Omega Constellation.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Jason Momoa arrives to the Leica 100-Year Exhibition" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/142946bb-356d-44a4-af9a-e2a42b031425/IMG_6747.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Longtime Leica enthusiast and actor Jason Momoa arrives at the Leica 100-Year Exhibition.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Single Owner Vintage Wakmann Chronograph, circa 1970s" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/52bcec93-26d7-4771-86df-d6460b862041/IMG_6751.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Single Owner Vintage Wakmann Chronograph, circa 1970s.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a photographer" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/54cf2f61-898e-4bed-ac35-518defb63ec3/IMG_6756.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Vintage Leica 1 circa 1929" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2a417827-eca3-4558-ac27-7392122d0ddf/IMG_6758.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Vintage Leica 1, circa 1929.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Vintage Leica 1 with telescopic viewfinder" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/92e65e93-dca6-49da-a4c7-7e1a11581fc4/IMG_6759.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Vintage Leica 1 with telescopic viewfinder.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica ZM 2" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6606d686-9818-4487-89ff-e72c4131a8f8/IMG_6767.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Leica ZM 2.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a watch" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/655bb216-be00-4bdd-a2dd-50ad94ebd01e/IMG_6773.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Rolex Explorer II Ref. 16570" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/516ec6be-3200-4c6e-9e3c-6e0948835213/IMG_6788.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Rolex Explorer II Ref. 16570.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Tudor Black Bay 58 GMT &amp; a vintage Leica 3 c circa 1946" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/3d4c7450-ed6e-4f22-ba35-757d7bab48d6/IMG_6791.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Tudor Black Bay 58 GMT &amp; a vintage Leica 3 c (circa 1946).&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Audemars Piguet Royal Oak Offshore 15720ST Diver Blue Dial" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/89974f8a-227e-4371-b2c8-23ac1d5bb130/IMG_6794.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Audemars Piguet Royal Oak Offshore 15720ST Diver Blue Dial.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Limited Edition Leica MP Grey Hammertone LHSA 1968-2003" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d2a81edf-e3ce-400a-bc9d-51ceea2f3d53/IMG_6798.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Limited Edition Leica MP Grey Hammertone LHSA 1968-2003.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="leica store" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2aff11e1-1460-4db4-bf33-30f1121b7655/IMG_6800.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="exhibition" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/468756c1-8b28-4e9e-a1bc-9ae23f028115/IMG_6801.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="18k White Gold Rolex GMT Master 2, ref. 116719 BLRO" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/705a3371-1a21-4c8b-8648-7b7dbc63ae35/IMG_6807.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>AN 18k White Gold Rolex GMT-Master II 126719.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a group of photographers" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/5942e085-aecd-42d7-976b-00687b3b97ae/IMG_6823.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Breitling Navitimer &amp; a slew of Leicas" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1eb61f4a-57cf-402c-961d-d370578a1c1d/IMG_6816.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Breitling Navitimer &amp; a gaggle of Leicas.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Photographer and Leica Ambassador Mathieu Bitton" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/27ef9c16-61f1-47aa-98fc-3f5ac2653c45/IMG_6825.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Photographer and Leica Ambassador Mathieu Bitton.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Rolex Datejust ref. 1603" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/c2f01d84-11eb-4b38-99b3-28e5cdb7956a/IMG_6834.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Rolex Datejust ref. 1603.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="F.P. Journe Chronomètre Souverain Havana Dial" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/7c38a8b7-a614-48ff-b87c-ab61244a77f3/IMG_6839.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A F.P. Journe Chronomètre Souverain Havana Dial.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Hugh &amp; Claudia Brownstone of Three Blind Men &amp; An Elephant" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/bdbbeaa5-9144-4bab-aee1-9cb4a12b534e/IMG_6849.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Hugh &amp; Claudia Brownstone of Three Blind Men &amp; An Elephant.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a photographer" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6c1043ed-585c-4836-a4c3-778e101c9ce3/IMG_6855.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Grand Seiko Spring Drive" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ab9ed331-a0cc-449b-b409-ee970ce94e4a/IMG_6857.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Grand Seiko Spring Drive model.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica ZM 1 Monochrom" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/ac252302-bf3d-4b2a-8a2a-fcf96a3e52d8/IMG_6871.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Leica ZM 1 Monochrom</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Tudor Pelagos" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/63214e2f-76bb-41cb-ae2f-7ee7734b7d56/IMG_6876.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Tudor Pelagos.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Cartier Roaster Chronograph" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/b1b739e0-f8f6-4387-b18d-014e83e0ebca/IMG_6880.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Cartier Roaster Chronograph.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a group of photographers" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/362f2a33-0f79-4441-9614-4eba6aeffbb3/IMG_6890.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Rolex Daytona Ref. 126500 LN" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/dc02e9a6-ba98-44a2-a54d-7f3afb1faeaa/IMG_6893.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Rolex Daytona Ref. 126500 LN.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Tag Heuer Formula 1 ref. 371.513" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6c8bded8-27b0-437c-b7ee-e3cb99771db2/IMG_6900.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Tag Heuer Formula 1 ref. 371.513.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Photographer Breana Helders Mazzagatte in Leica&#39;s SL3 Campaign" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1221d279-ca2b-4bbe-824b-a3e79dc5829a/IMG_6929.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Photographer Breana Helders Mazzagatte in Leica's SL3 Campaign.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Jason Momoa takes the stage for a private performance with his band ÖOF TATATÁ" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/6d8e0312-5dcc-41c0-87a4-8121359398e1/IMG_6952.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Jason Momoa takes the stage for a private performance with his band ÖOF TATATÁ.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="ÖOF TATATÁ front man Mike Hayes" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/2cf61c71-a2bf-4b3e-858c-f9e8d4f8a53e/IMG_6973.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>ÖOF TATATÁ front man Mike Hayes.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Patek Philippe Aquanaut 5261R-001" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/02d97eeb-8685-4ce5-ada0-b50e72f5b6f4/IMG_6982.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Patek Philippe Aquanaut 5261R-001.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Jason Momoa" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/8bf7698e-a280-40e0-be40-5513e988ea10/IMG_7028.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="a photographer" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/07186434-a06b-43d6-8fc8-ce9a3ce60b71/IMG_7101.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Timex World Time Reissue 39mm" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/76f8b22b-4f32-463d-bfaf-aff1a991b1b2/IMG_7116.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A Timex World Time Reissue 39mm.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Leica NYC" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a9e57cf1-27c2-4837-be29-eed49d0e007e/IMG_7120.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="The band" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/10f9ad72-743a-4892-ac29-384c023ee90b/IMG_7124.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Momoa" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/93022e2a-58e3-400d-8ca6-0cc7e5006b03/IMG_7202.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Jason Momoa wearing a Leica ZM 1 Gold Limited Edition" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/be8fa152-f186-4010-ba1a-8377f2cdc55f/IMG_7277.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Jason Momoa wearing a Leica ZM 1 Gold Limited Edition.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<figure>
  <img alt="Rolex GMT 1675/3" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/d3f80a8f-c825-4bdd-81e1-00f9248bd04a/IMG_7279.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>A vintage Rolex GMT 1675/3 'Rootbeer'.&nbsp;</p></figcaption>
</figure>

]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/1bd78581-6642-46cd-9cc2-2bb41d3900f8/leica-header.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Photo Report: Watch (And Camera) Spotting At Leica’s Centennial Celebration In NYC</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business News: Omega CEO And Other Top Watch Industry Executives Say Tariff Uncertainty May Delay Purchases By Some Consumers </title>
      <dc:creator>Andy  Hoffman</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/omega-ceo-and-other-top-watch-industry-executives-say-tariff-uncertainty-may-delay-purchases-by-some</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/omega-ceo-and-other-top-watch-industry-executives-say-tariff-uncertainty-may-delay-purchases-by-some</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Omega will promote 60-year anniversary of NASA certification with new models despite surprise tariffs announcement making sales more difficult, CEO Raynald Aeschlimann says.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a85a5b9b-0bba-40a1-8a12-f9185fcbe0f2/omega-tarrifs-speedmaster-2025-1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	<p>The economic uncertainty created by dramatic shifts in U.S. trade policy, including tariffs on Swiss watches, could cause consumers to delay purchasing high-end timepieces, the Chief Executive Officer of Omega says. "The world was shaken,'' by the tariffs, Raynald Aeschlimann said in Biel at an event to highlight Omega's 60-year anniversary since winning NASA qualification for the Speedmaster model to be issued to astronauts on manned space flights and become the first watch worn on the moon.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="Omega CEO Raynald Aeschlimann" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/649fe33c-7acc-427c-a316-a67934b5a39a/omega-tarrifs-speedmaster-2025-3.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption><p>Raynald Aeschlimann, CEO of Omega SA</p></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>"Shaken because there's uncertainty about what's going to happen with the economy, what's going to happen with everybody's development, and that's something that doesn't help us to create this shopping moment,'' Aeschlimann said.</p>

<p>In response to U.S. tariffs that currently stand at 10%, as well as the rise in the value of the Swiss franc against the dollar since the surprise April announcement, Omega increased prices in some markets on May 1 including a rise of 5% in the U.S. Several other brands including top seller Rolex have also raised U.S. prices following the tariffs.<br><br>The initial 31% tariff on Swiss goods announced in April by the Trump administration was paused for 90 days after equity and bond markets swooned on the news. Trade officials from nations impacted by the tariffs are now working to strike new trade deals while a 10% levy remains in place. The Omega CEO said he is concerned that if high tariff levels continue, the brand may have to push prices further and move beyond its current $7,500 average selling price.</p>

<p>This is a big year for Omega as the brand is marking the 1965 anniversary of the Speedmaster being certified by NASA for space missions and besting rival brands, including Rolex and Longines. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="an Omega speedmaster in hand" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/5696e84a-2509-4351-818b-092762577492/omega-tarrifs-speedmaster-2025-2.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Omega is one of the five largest Swiss watch brands by sales, financial analysts estimate, and accounted for about one-third of sales from brands owned by Swatch Group AG in 2024, according to estimates by Switzerland's Vontobel.<br><br>Some consumers will reflexively become protective and reconsider buying a watch until there is more clarity on the economic impact of the policy shifts, Aeschlimann said. Regardless of those challenges, Omega will mark the anniversary with promotions and new models highlighting the brand's long association with space exploration.</p>
  	<p>"We're going into it, we're creating, we're going to spend money, we're going to do events, and we're launching new products,'' he said. Aeschlimann wouldn't say if Omega would unveil a new Snoopy Speedmaster model this year to mark the NASA certification. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="an Omega Speedmaster chronograph" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/72e1f0b1-a4b6-4b75-b35b-b6ef25491bea/omega-tarrifs-speedmaster-20254.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>It's been five years since Omega introduced a new version of the Peanuts character-themed timepiece that remains a top seller and difficult-to-acquire watch for consumers. Golfer Rory McIlroy <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/rory-mcilroy-finally-completes-the-career-grand-slam-in-style" target="">wore a Silver Snoopy Award</a> Speedmaster after winning the Masters golf tournament this year and completing a career grand slam.</p>
  	<p>The Omega CEO's statements about shaken consumer sentiment follow similar comments made by other top Swiss watch executives. Ilaria Resta, the Chief Executive Officer of Audemars Piguet told an online conference held by IMD in Switzerland last month that the independent Swiss brand, which is marking its 150th anniversary in 2025, remained bullish on the long-term growth prospects of the luxury watch sector, but that the uncertainty caused by the changes in U.S. trade policy were making consumers hesitant in the short-term.<br><br>"People about to buy a significant item like a watch or a car, they are in standby mode," Resta said.</p>
  	<p>An Audemars Piguet spokesperson confirmed the independent watchmaker had "implemented selective price adjustments in the U.S.,'' after the changes in trade policy and the price of gold jumped to record highs.</p>

<p>"This decision was made in response to global trade developments and rising material costs. These updates are essential for us to continue delivering the highest standards of craftsmanship and service worldwide,'' the AP spokesperson said. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="AP royal Oak blue ceramic" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/45537abc-4fa1-4e4f-b7a4-9bf6db1fe7bb/20250409_APBlueCeramics_080.JPG?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Meanwhile, executives at the major watch auction houses say they are also bracing to see if the uncertainty caused by the tariffs will impact prices and demand at the Geneva auctions this month. Antiquorum Managing Director and Watch Expert Julien Schaerer said about one-third of Antiquorum clients are based in the U.S. and that a 31% tariff on watches would be potentially devastating if it were to be implemented. "These political storms are happening every other day, so I'm not panicking until something is really decided for good,'' Schaerer said.</p>
  	<p>For more information visit <a href="https://www.omegawatches.com/chronicle/1962-the-first-speedmaster-in-space" target="_blank">Omega</a>, <a href="https://www.audemarspiguet.com/com/en/home.html?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=ch_en_bra_pure-brand_apmk_google_sea_traffic_exact&amp;utm_content=brand&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=12662810599&amp;gbraid=0AAAAADOip0sKSYj3sXpP2P0frPgU_cH7K&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjw2tHABhCiARIsANZzDWo8dWHZmjTbX32e8gdBe5KGLUNFoo46mYqbQJ6RmOzyDkFXRf7x8rkaAh2VEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank">Audemars Piquet</a>, and <a href="https://live.antiquorum.swiss/" target="_blank">Antiquorum</a> online. </p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/a85a5b9b-0bba-40a1-8a12-f9185fcbe0f2/omega-tarrifs-speedmaster-2025-1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Business News: Omega CEO And Other Top Watch Industry Executives Say Tariff Uncertainty May Delay Purchases By Some Consumers </media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Tudor Pelagos FXD Chrono “Pink” For Giro d'Italia  2025</title>
      <dc:creator>Andy  Hoffman</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 10:30:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <link>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-2</link>
      <guid>https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-2</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tudor's new cycling-specific limited edition chronograph for the famed Italian bike race. </p>]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[  <img alt="" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/eb493399-3de0-45bc-adee-7755c2664805/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  	

  	<h3>What We Know</h3>

  	<p>Less than a week after launching its Formula 1-themed carbon fibre <a href="https://www.hodinkee.com/articles/the-tudor-black-bay-chrono-carbon-25" target="_blank">Black Bay 'Chrono 25'</a>, Tudor is dropping another new carbon chronograph, this one in a cycling-specific format to celebrate the <a href="https://www.giroditalia.it/en/" target="_blank">Giro d'Italia </a>and the brand's role as official timekeeper for the race. The Pelagos FXD Chrono "Pink'' is, at its core, a new colorway edition of the Pelagos FXD Chrono 'Cycling Edition' launched by the brand ahead of the event last year. While that one gave a nod to the red and black livery of the Tudor Pro Cycling Team, this new model pays specific tribute to the pink jersey or 'Maglia Rosa' worn by the leader and winner of the Italian Grand Tour.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="tudor fxd chrono pink" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/00e543b9-d0a2-4a93-982f-f76043844639/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-4.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>What sets the "Pink'' apart is the rose colorway for the cycling-oriented tachymeter scale and a black fabric strap featuring the same color striping. Tudor says it will produce just 300 of the 43 millimeter diameter carbon composite cased models with fixed lugs that incorporate titanium in the screw-down crown and pushers for added strength and durability. The case remains 13.2 millimeters thick, and the caseback markings reinforce the connection to cycling.<br><br>Featuring a black matt dial, Tudor's signature snowflake hour hand and square lume plot hour markers, the "Pink" has a 60-minute graduated fixed bezel and a 45-minute subdial counter.  What makes it a cycling-specific watch is the chronograph's tachymeter scale that wraps around the dial circularly and is oriented for cycling speed, not motorsports, allowing the wearer to calculate their pedal-turning velocity over a set distance.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="tudor fxd chrono pink" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/81bc7a35-e1b3-429b-af30-b1febfe0eb00/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-2.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Powered by Tudor's MT5813 chronograph caliber, the "Pink" has a 70-hour power reserve, beats at 4Hz, and is COSC certified. It is limited to 300 pieces, each with a price of $5600.</p>
  	<h3>What We Think</h3>

  	<p>Cycling-specific watches are a relatively novel development in the watch world, as professional riders have traditionally eschewed timepieces during race time. But that's all changing with a slew of riders wearing watches in the peloton and more brands taking part in the popular sport that's a fixture on the European sporting calendar. Tudor has rapidly become a significant force in cycling through its sponsorship of the Fabian Cancellara-owned Tudor Pro Cycling Team that's been racking up the victories this year. This summer, the Tudor squad will compete for the first time in the biggest Grand Tour of them all, the Tour de France, thanks to a wildcard entry.</p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="tudor fxd chrono pink" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/72298068-e5dc-4798-a219-e12a51c6aaa9/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-5.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<p>Currently sponsored by Swatch Group AG's Tissot brand, the Tour de France leader and winner wears a yellow jersey in contrast to the Giro-themed shade of the new Tudor "Pink." Save for the strap and placement of some the the pink accents, the new Tudor limited edition is strikingly similar to the<a href="https://www.tudorwatch.com/en/tudor-mag/news/wins-and-watches-at-the-2024-giro-d-italia" target=""><u> one-off Tudor watch</u></a> that was awarded to last year's Giro d'Italia winner and Richard Mille sponsored Tadej Pogacar who gamely accepted the timepiece as part of the reward for his grueling victory of Italy's most prestigious cycling race.</p>
  	<p>There's no doubt that, for some, the new colorway and association with the Giro adds a coolness factor to the new "Pink.'' The shade is most certainly in vogue among more watch enthusiasts. Recall the reaction to the limited Black Bay Chronograph with a pink dial released last year that saw prices for the model soar on secondary markets. Perhaps Tudor is hoping for something similar with the brand's latest limited edition offering. </p>
  	<figure>
  <img alt="tudor fxd chrono pink" src="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/f30737ae-8164-4aed-94b7-d937895ee415/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-3.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;ch=Width%2CDPR%2CSave-Data&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=2000" />
  <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>

  	<h2>The Basics</h2>

  	<p><strong>Brand:</strong> Tudor <br><strong>Model:</strong> Pelagos FXD Chrono "Pink"<br><strong>Reference Number: </strong>25827KNRS</p>

<p><strong>Diameter:</strong> 43mm<br><strong>Thickness:</strong> 13.2mm <br><strong>Case Material:</strong> Black carbon composite<br><strong>Dial Color:</strong> Black, with pink accents<br><strong>Indexes:</strong> Applied, luminous<br><strong>Water Resistance:</strong> 100 meters (330ft)<br><strong>Strap/Bracelet: </strong>Single-piece black fabric strap with pink stripe</p>
  	<h2>The Movement</h2>

  	<p><strong>Caliber:</strong> Manufacture Calibre MT5813<br><strong>Functions:</strong> Hours, minutes, seconds, date, 45-minute chronograph measure<br><strong>Power Reserve:</strong> 70 Hours<br><strong>Winding:</strong> Automatic<br><strong>Frequency:</strong> 28,800 vph (4 Hz)<br><strong>Chronometer Certified:</strong> Yes, COSC </p>
  	<h2>Pricing & Availability</h2>

  	<p><strong>Price:</strong> $5,600<br><strong>Limited Edition: </strong>Yes, 300 pieces. </p>

<p>For more, <a href="https://www.tudorwatch.com/en/tudor-mag/news/pink-limited-model" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p>
]]>
      </content:encoded>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://hodinkee.imgix.net/uploads/images/eb493399-3de0-45bc-adee-7755c2664805/tudor-pelagos-fxd-chrono-pink-1.jpg?ixlib=rails-1.1.0&amp;fm=jpg&amp;q=55&amp;auto=format&amp;usm=12&amp;w=2000" medium="image" isDefault="true">
        <media:title type="plain">Introducing: The Tudor Pelagos FXD Chrono “Pink” For Giro d'Italia  2025</media:title>
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
