<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Retro Dodo]]></title><description><![CDATA[Retro Gaming News, Reviews & Stories]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/</link><image><url>https://retrododo.com/favicon.png</url><title>Retro Dodo</title><link>https://retrododo.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 5.119</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:41:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://retrododo.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Unreleased N64 Game Dinosaur Planet Gets The N64 Recompiled Treatment]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If you&apos;re sitting there thinking that that looks a lot like Krystal from Star For Adventures, then you&apos;d be right. Dinosaur Planet was developed by Rare and was supposed to come out for the N64 to join the ranks of Donkey Kong 64 and Banjo-Kazooie, but</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/unreleased-n64-game-dinosaur-planet-gets-the-n64-recompiled-treatment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681df1869202b10001ce976d</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 12:43:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/dinosaur-planet-n64.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/dinosaur-planet-n64.jpg" alt="Unreleased N64 Game Dinosaur Planet Gets The N64 Recompiled Treatment"><p>If you&apos;re sitting there thinking that that looks a lot like Krystal from Star For Adventures, then you&apos;d be right. Dinosaur Planet was developed by Rare and was supposed to come out for the N64 to join the ranks of Donkey Kong 64 and Banjo-Kazooie, but it never happened, instead joining the Star Fox universe and becoming one of my <a href="https://retrododo.com/best-gamecube-games/" rel="noreferrer">favourite GameCube games</a>. </p><p>The <a href="https://retrododo.com/n64recomp-provides-a-native-pc-port-of-majoras-mask-with-other-games-possibly-on-the-way/" rel="noreferrer">N64 Recompiled tool</a> has been used to create native PC ports of lots of existing games like Majora&apos;s Mask since it appeared last year, and now a user has taken the beta build of Dinosaur Planet that appeared in February 2000 and created an initial native PC port for the unreleased game on GitHub. </p><p>According to <a href="https://gbatemp.net/threads/unreleased-dinosaur-planet-n64-game-by-rare-gets-an-initial-recompilation-port-using-n64-recompiled.670742/?ref=retrododo.com">GBATemp</a>, GitHub user <a href="https://github.com/Francessco121?ref=retrododo.com" rel="nofollow ugc noopener">Francessco121</a> has recompiled the beta build that surfaced 5 years ago which modders have been working on to fix glitched portions and unfinished sequences. Now, it also has modding support, WIP Widescreen support, and a higher resolution.</p><p>For any old-school Rare fans, the fact that the game is now playable natively on PC is fantastic, though there&apos;s still a virtual list of things that need to be worked on, like ironing out any remaining bugs and adding a higher framerate. But now that the spotlight is on Dinosaur Planet and more people have access to it, there&apos;s a chance that we might have a community-created game sooner than we could have ever dreamed of. </p><p>As a Starfox Adventures fan, I would love to experience the full Dinosaur Planet game in all its glory, especially if it could be brought back onto an N64 cartridge to play on original hardware too - that&apos;s one cardboard box that would be going straight into a plastic cover!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gex Trilogy Physical Pre-Order Dates & Bundles Announced]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Gex fans around the world have been eagerly awaiting more details on the return of gaming&apos;s most famous gecko, and now Limited Run Games have finally announced the release date of the new collection as well as the three collector&apos;s bundles that are dropping. Pre-orders for</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/gex-trilogy-physical-pre-order-dates-bundles-announced/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681ddf5d9202b10001ce96d7</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:52:26 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-limited-run-games.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-limited-run-games.jpg" alt="Gex Trilogy Physical Pre-Order Dates &amp; Bundles Announced"><p>Gex fans around the world have been eagerly awaiting more details on the return of gaming&apos;s most famous gecko, and now Limited Run Games have finally announced the release date of the new collection as well as the three collector&apos;s bundles that are dropping. Pre-orders for the physical editions are open from today, May 9th, 2025, at 10 am EDT, with the games releasing on PC and consoles digitally from June 16th. And yes, the Tail Time package comes with a 36&quot; inflatable Gex doll... because why not!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tq1P2Vu8v5o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Gex Trilogy | New Features!"></iframe></figure><p>We spoke to the Limited Run Games team about <a href="https://retrododo.com/gex-is-back-interviewing-limited-run-games-on-re-releasing-the-original-trilogy/" rel="noreferrer">bringing Gex back for modern audiences</a> and some of the quality of life features that will be coming to the games like upscaling, rewind (thanks <a href="https://retrododo.com/lets-talk-retro-jordan-mechner/" rel="noreferrer">Jordan Mechner</a> for creating that!) and being able to save anywhere. My favourite Gex Game, Gex: Enter the Gecko alongside Gex 3: Deep Cover Gecko, both now support 16:9 widescreen with full 360 analogue controls too! </p><p>First up in the release bundle collection is the standard edition, priced at $39.99 is simply a boxed edition of the game collection with all three games on it.  You&apos;ll also get a booklet for those old-school vibes. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-lrg-standard-release.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Gex Trilogy Physical Pre-Order Dates &amp; Bundles Announced" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/gex-lrg-standard-release.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/gex-lrg-standard-release.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-lrg-standard-release.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Then there&apos;s the classic collection, which costs $79.99. It comes with a Retro-style PS1 box to take you straight back to the 90s, a steelbook, a double-sided poster of Gex, and a soundtrack CD with selected songs from the Gex games. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-lrg-classic-edition.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Gex Trilogy Physical Pre-Order Dates &amp; Bundles Announced" loading="lazy" width="1080" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/gex-lrg-classic-edition.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/gex-lrg-classic-edition.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/gex-lrg-classic-edition.jpg 1080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>The Tall Time Edition is the ultimate Gex collectors&apos; package with a premium price of $199.99. As well as everything in the classic edition (minus the select soundtrack in favour of a Full Soundtrack CD), you&apos;ll get a 36&#x201D; inflatable Gex doll, a 7&#x201D; Gex statue, Gex trading cards, a remote pin, and a collector&#x2019;s box with artwork by Yoshitaka Amano. </p><p>Pre-orders end on July 6th with an estimated shipping date Oct 24&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;31. <a href="https://limitedrungames.com/search?q=gex&amp;options%5Bprefix%5D=last&amp;ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer">Head to Limited Run Games</a> to check out all the bundles as well as T-Shirts, Skate Decks, and more!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[LEGO Finally Shines A Light On An Icon From Our Childhoods In New Set]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>How many films have you seen with this little lamp in it? Pixar films basically ruled my childhood, and Luxo Jr was just as important to me as all of the other <a href="https://retrododo.com/90s-toys/" rel="noreferrer">&apos;90s characters</a> I used to think about on a daily basis when I should have been learning</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/lego-finally-shines-a-light-on-an-icon-from-our-childhoods-in-new-set/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681dc5569202b10001ce9683</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 09:25:52 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pixar-lego-set.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pixar-lego-set.jpg" alt="LEGO Finally Shines A Light On An Icon From Our Childhoods In New Set"><p>How many films have you seen with this little lamp in it? Pixar films basically ruled my childhood, and Luxo Jr was just as important to me as all of the other <a href="https://retrododo.com/90s-toys/" rel="noreferrer">&apos;90s characters</a> I used to think about on a daily basis when I should have been learning how to become an upstanding citizen (I finally know my times tables at least...).  </p><p>LEGO have announced that Luxo Jr. will be available to build in brick form for the very first time after teaming up with Pixar to create the LEGO Ideas Luxo Jr Collectible Display model. Yes, this is further proof that the LEGO Ideas programme works wonders, with London-based LEGO fan Toby Brett paying homage to a character that had a profound impact on his childhood, just like it did mine. After receiving the necessary 10,000 votes and making it through the panel stage to complete his project, he said that the mascot <em>&apos;perfectly sums up my love for these [Pixar] movies. I spent a lot of time looking at photos of Luxo Jr. to make my model as screen-accurate and recognisable as possible</em>&apos;, and you&apos;ve got to agree that he&apos;s done a fantastic job. </p><p>To say that Luxo Jr. has been around since 1986, a LEGO version has been a long time coming. Still, at least when the set arrives on the 1st of June this year, it will arrive before the little lamp turns 40 years old... wow, that made me feel very old all of a sudden. </p><p>The set will be fully movable and comes with the iconic Pixar ball to flatten. There are hidden easter eggs inside the ball too to take your mind back to classic Disney films of the past like Toy Story, Monsters Inc., and Up. The set is made up of 613 pieces and costs &#xA3;59.99. The good news is that <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-gb/product/%C7%80-disney-pixar-luxo-jr-21357?ref=retrododo.com">you can pre-order it from today</a>, with the official sales starting on June 1st. </p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It&apos;s been a long time since a frog has taken centre stage as the protagonist in a video game. Sure, we&apos;ve had Frogger hop into the limelight over the years, and Kermit has had his stint in video games, but since Glenn from Chrono Trigger and</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/kero-kero-cowboy-review/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681cbe5d9202b10001ce94f5</guid><category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 18:00:36 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/kerokerocowboy-review.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/kerokerocowboy-review.jpg" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West"><p>It&apos;s been a long time since a frog has taken centre stage as the protagonist in a video game. Sure, we&apos;ve had Frogger hop into the limelight over the years, and Kermit has had his stint in video games, but since Glenn from Chrono Trigger and Slippy Toad of Fox McCloud&apos;s crew, the only croaking amphibians we&apos;ve had to turn to have been the Frog Choir from Ocarina of Time. Well, Mike Bedsole, aka <a href="https://metagamemike.itch.io/?ref=retrododo.com">Metagame Mike</a>, has finally righted that wrong with the release of his new Game Boy game Kero Kero Cowboy, featuring a gun-slinging, cowboy-hat-wearing, rootin-tootin frog with a thirst for justice!</p><p>I first covered the news of Kero Kero Cowboy back when Mike contacted Retro Dodo to <a href="https://retrododo.com/kero-kero-cowboy-is-a-new-game-boy-color-game-inspired-by-mario-yoshi-the-wild-west/" rel="noreferrer">chat about the demo for the game</a> and instantly gelled with it; it&apos;s classic side-scrolling platforming action with hints of all of my favourite Game Boy games from my childhood. There was just one problem - I wanted to experience more! So, when Mike emailed me again to say that the game was finally finished and available for the masses to download and play, I jumped at the chance to put it through its paces for you guys. </p><p><strong>*NB - There will be spoilers throughout this article, but in the interest of keeping things mysterious, I&apos;ve only used images up to World 3 of the game. You&apos;ll have to support Mike and buy the game to see the rest!</strong></p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div class="cg-box-layout-review  " style="--cg-theme-color:#B48CD0"><div class="cg-review-box"><div class="cg-tbl-rate-svg"><div class="cb-tbl-value">9</div><svg viewbox="0 0 32 32" width="64" height="64" data-percent="89" style="stroke-dasharray: 71.578, 999;"><circle cx="16" cy="16" r="12.80"/></svg></div><div class="cg-review-title">Metagame Mike&apos;s Game Boy Color Title Frogmarches It&apos;s Way To Brilliance With Great Graphics &amp; A Loveable Protagonist</div><div class="cg-review-bar-row"><span class="cg-review-bar-title">Gameplay</span><span class="cg-review-bar-score">8.5</span><div class="cg-review-bar" style="--cg-review:85%;"></div></div><div class="cg-review-bar-row"><span class="cg-review-bar-title">Graphics</span><span class="cg-review-bar-score">9</span><div class="cg-review-bar" style="--cg-review:90%;"></div></div><div class="cg-review-bar-row"><span class="cg-review-bar-title">Compatability</span><span class="cg-review-bar-score">8</span><div class="cg-review-bar" style="--cg-review:80%;"></div></div><div class="cg-review-bar-row"><span class="cg-review-bar-title">Easy To Play</span><span class="cg-review-bar-score">9</span><div class="cg-review-bar" style="--cg-review:90%;"></div></div><div class="cg-review-bar-row"><span class="cg-review-bar-title">Price/Value For Money</span><span class="cg-review-bar-score">10</span><div class="cg-review-bar" style="--cg-review:100%;"></div></div><div class="cg-text"><p>Kero Kero Cowboy brings shades of Yoshi, Kirby, Ducktales, and Lucky Luke together and fuses them with a lovable lilypad-dwelling character that you can&apos;t help but root for. The gameplay pays homage to all of my favourite side-scrollers and is perfect for gamers of any age to have a go at. The bosses are a little on the easy side, but the levels themselves are fun to play and provide a nice level of replayability for the 101% completionists out there.&#xA0;</p>            </div></div></div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<ul><li><strong>Price:</strong>&#xA0;$9.99</li><li><strong>Compatible With:</strong>&#xA0; Game Boy Color emulators, EverDrive, Analogue Pocket.</li><li><strong>Playtime:</strong>&#xA0;6-8 Hours</li><li><strong>Available From:</strong>&#xA0;<a href="https://metagamemike.itch.io/kero-kero-cowboy?ref=retrododo.com">Itch.io</a></li></ul><h2 id="spur-tacular-gameplay-with-a-toadally-awesome-hero">Spur-tacular Gameplay With A Toadally Awesome Hero </h2><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-1.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-1.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-1.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Kero Kero Cowboy takes me straight back to wielding a Game Boy Color towards the end of the 90s. The color palette is fantastic, as are the characters and the levels you&apos;ll encounter as you progress through the game. This is a digital-download game that doesn&apos;t come on a cartridge, so you&apos;ll need an Analogue Pocket, an emulator, or an EverDrive to play it on your original hardware. I would absolutely love to have a physical copy of this game, and if ModRetro are reading this, then maybe it might happen one day!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div><p>I&apos;m getting ahead of myself - before we go any further, let me give you a brief introduction to the world of Kero Kero Cowboy, a frog with a mission to rid the west of villainy. You&apos;re tasked with taking down the Ferocious Five, a motley crew of wanted criminals who act as the world bosses for each of the game&apos;s 5 stages. Kero has multiple moves that I&apos;ll get onto in a second and is a great shot with a pistol despite not being able to see from underneath his hat - I guess you&apos;ve either got skills or you don&apos;t!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gamepay-5.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gamepay-5.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gamepay-5.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gamepay-5.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>I&apos;ve never met the game&apos;s creator Mike before, but I can already tell that he grew up playing the same games as me. Any level with a minecart section in it instantly takes my mind back to playing Donkey Kong Country as a kid, and while this is far more relaxing than having DK plummeting to his doom amongst a horde of angry King K.Rool&apos;s minions, it&apos;s nice to pick out different ideas from titles that might have influenced Mike in the designing and building process of this addictive little game. </p><h2 id="reach-for-the-sky-and-then-select-your-level">Reach For The Sky (And Then Select Your Level)</h2><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/keo-kero-cowboy-title-screen.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/keo-kero-cowboy-title-screen.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/keo-kero-cowboy-title-screen.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/keo-kero-cowboy-title-screen.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Picking a level is usually such a mundane job, but it feels much more fun when you&apos;re faced with a shooting range to choose which stage you&apos;re going to tackle. I haven&apos;t experienced anything like this since I picked my passport save file in <a href="https://retrododo.com/best-n64-games/" rel="noreferrer">GoldenEye 007</a>, and it&apos;s the perfect way to celebrate all things Wild West. There are 5 worlds and 5 standard stages on each - 4 levels and a boss battle. There <em>is</em> a bonus level on each stage if you get enough special coins, many of which are hidden behind segments of rock that need blasting away with your pistol. As you can see above, I didn&apos;t manage to find them all on my first play through, but I&apos;ve been back since and made up for it. </p><p>One thing I will say to Mike&apos;s credit is that all of the worlds feel inherently different to one another - the levels within each world all have an overarching theme that ties them together, but the colours and the level structure are different enough to make you feel like you&apos;re somewhere completely new rather than just rehashing old ideas which, as we all know, can be something that Game Boy games fall into the trap of, especially when they aren&apos;t graphically enticing. The worlds get progressively harder as you move through the game too, but not with a level of difficulty that would provide a challenge to hardened NES gamers (though I&apos;ll get onto this in a minute). </p><h2 id="saddle-up-learn-the-ropes">Saddle Up &amp; Learn The Ropes</h2><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/kKero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/kKero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/kKero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/kKero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Kero Kero has some ace moves up his sleeve (do frogs have sleeves?) that gamers can pull out to thwart enemies along the way. And while we&apos;re on the subject of enemies, I really like the different personalities that Mike has given to all of the character sprites - how often are you going to see a bandit crab or a fly wearing a Stetson? </p><p>Pressing the attack button sends out a big frog tongue to ensnare enemies, allowing you to spit them back out as a weapon to take down other bad guys. Yes, it&apos;s a cross between Yoshi and Kirby, but I&apos;m not angry about it, and it works as we&apos;re dealing with a frog, after all. Still, with no enemy hidden inside his mouth, players can press select to bring up Kero Kero Cowboy&apos;s six-shooter. </p><p>You&apos;ll need to use your gun to take down enemies that are too far away to grab with your tongue or that will prevent you from jumping onto a ledge where they might be meandering around. It&apos;s a nice little touch, and I like the fact that the pistol is as big as Kero Kero - never mind a French frog; that&apos;s one hench frog!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-3.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Obviously, frogs are amphibians, so Kero Kero&apos;s skills aren&apos;t just limited to being on land. See how he&apos;s full of air? You can push out a pocket of air to defeat enemies like Crabby Wayne over there (made-up name, don&apos;t send Mike hate for how bad it is), and pushing up on the D-pad at the surface of the water makes you hop up high to reach ledges.</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-blue"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x1F399;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Listen back on&#xA0;<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/2zAlKOkLB6542lrrVoQ4E6?si=d56a86a11f544a20&amp;ref=retrododo.com">Spotify</a>,&#xA0;<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/retro-dodo-podcast-retro-gaming-news-interviews-and/id1531325023?ref=retrododo.com">Apple Podcasts</a>, or wherever you get your podcasts! You can also watch full episodes of our interviews on&#xA0;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@retrododopodcast?ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer">YouTube</a>&#xA0;channel too!&#xA0;</div></div><p>When you aren&apos;t in water, hopping comes in the form of a large cowboy boot that you jump into. This allows you to stand on spikes and bounce on top of cacti, which are the only enemies you can&apos;t defeat with your pistol or by firing enemies at. Again, everything sticks true to the Wild West theme, although spitting fire after eating a chili pepper isn&apos;t something that I ever saw Clint Eastwood do. </p><h3 id="checkpoint-in-by-the-campfire">Check(Point) In By The Campfire</h3><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-4.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-4.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-4.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-4.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>This little dog is probably my favorite character in the whole game, other than Kero Kero. To save at a checkpoint, you&apos;ll need to have 10 coins in the bank to spend on cooking a sausage around a campfire. If you don&apos;t have any money, you can always exchange a life for $100 to use throughout the game, but coins aren&apos;t hard to come by (unless you hit a game over and lose them all!). Sitting by the fire replenishes your health and ammo too, as well as giving you a place to come back to when you lose a life, so if you&apos;re getting a bit trigger-happy with your six-shooter and going in all-guns-blazing to no avail, this poochyy prospector is one to look out for. </p><h2 id="boss-battles">Boss Battles</h2><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-2.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Kero Kero Cowboy Review: Hop Into An Epic Adventure With The Wildest Frog In The West" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-2.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-2.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Kero-Kero-Cowboy-Gameplay-2.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>There&apos;s a boss battle with one of the Ferocious Five at the end of each stage. Unsurprisingly, the boss of Mole Mines was a mole called Pickaxe Pete, and he was a tenacious little critter too. All of the bosses can be defeated within around six hits, which in this case is how many bullets I had in my pistol. Still, if you run out, it&apos;s simply a case of swallowing whatever weapon or shield the boss is using and firing it back at them. </p><p>The boss battles aren&apos;t as hard as what I&apos;ve experienced in games like <a href="https://retrododo.com/baby-t-rex-review/" rel="noreferrer">Baby T-Rex</a>, so hardened players might find it a bit of an easy ride. That&apos;s the main reason I&apos;ve given Kero Kero Cowboy 9 instead of 10. If you grew up with the likes of Super Mario All-Stars, then it&apos;ll be a walk in the park, but hey, not everyone is looking for extreme difficulty, and it&apos;s still an enjoyable game to get lost in, regardless.</p><h3 id="a-rootin-tootin-soundtrack">A Rootin&apos;-Tootin&apos; Soundtrack</h3><p>No 8-bit game is complete without its soundtrack, and Scott Semanski has done a great job of instilling each of the levels with its own theme to get you pumped while playing. Scott&apos;s work is famous within the GB Studio world, so it&apos;s no surprise that Mike has pulled him in to create an enticing atmosphere for Kero Kero&apos;s adventure. There&apos;s also a music player that you can access to listen to the tunes without the gameplay if you want to imagine what it might be like to hop through the desert in a giant cowboy boot - we&apos;ve all got to have dreams, right?</p><h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<div class="cg-pc-box-four"><div class="cg-pc-row"><div class="cg-item-pros  cg-green "><div class="cg-pros-name">Pros</div><ul><li>Colourful adventure with an exciting hero</li><li>Innovative weapons and abilities</li><li>Easy to play, no matter your gaming ability</li><li>Unlocking bonus levels makes the experience last longer</li></ul>            </div><div class="cg-item-cons  cg-red "><div class="cg-cons-name">Cons</div><ul><li value="1">The game isn&apos;t very long or difficult, so don&apos;t expect to be playing it for months on end</li></ul>            </div></div></div>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>As I said above, it&apos;s about time we had a frog stepping back into the limelight in gaming without having to worry about it being crushed by oncoming traffic. Kero Kero joins Croc, Yoshi, and Yooka in the world of sidescrolling green machines, and while he&apos;s a new kid on the block, he&apos;s proved to me over the past couple of days that he knows how to handle himself when the going gets tough. </p><p>Game length-wise, you&apos;re realistically looking at around 6-8 hours of gameplay when playing through Kero Kero Cowboy, though to say the game only costs $9.99, I would say that&apos;s about right and in line with the difficulty of the title too. I would still say it was fair if it came in at $25 in a physical cartridge and a colour manual and box for the collectors out there too, but as a download-only title, less than $10 seems fair to me. </p><p>Would I have liked it to be a little harder? Sure, but I do review games for a living, so I&apos;m used to playing through titles pretty fast. Most importantly, Mike has managed to capture that feeling of experiencing games like Pocahontas and Toy Story for the first time as a kid, of turning on Kirby&apos;s Dream Land and immersing yourself in a new and exciting world. I&apos;m a big fan of Kero Kero Cowboy, and I hope you&apos;ll check it out too!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Podcast #003 - Searching For Collectibles In Akihabara, Japan]]></title><link>https://retrododo.com/podcast-003-searching-for-collectibles-in-akihabara-japan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681caca19202b10001ce9468</guid><category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:14:49 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/cc003.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Channel The Spirit Of The Hero Of Time With Nintendo's Legend Of Zelda Series Selects]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Just when I thought my work home was going to be accompanied by the same old metal songs again, a notification pops up on my phone telling me that Nintendo has just added epic tunes from the Legend of Zelda series to the Nintendo Music App. </p><p>With 18 tracks spanning</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/channel-the-spirit-of-the-hero-of-time-with-nintendos-legend-of-zelda-series-selects/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681b867d9202b10001ce9414</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:21:45 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Zelda-series-selects.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Zelda-series-selects.jpg" alt="Channel The Spirit Of The Hero Of Time With Nintendo&apos;s Legend Of Zelda Series Selects"><p>Just when I thought my work home was going to be accompanied by the same old metal songs again, a notification pops up on my phone telling me that Nintendo has just added epic tunes from the Legend of Zelda series to the Nintendo Music App. </p><p>With 18 tracks spanning from the original The Legend of Zelda game on the NES through to Breath of the Wild and an order that changes daily, you can relive classic moments from the series wherever you are, whether on a walk, on the treadmill, or LARPing as Link in a field somewhere. The playlist lasts 45 minutes and has the title theme from The Wind Waker, the Hyrule Field Main Theme from Ocarina of Time, Fi&apos;s theme from Skyward Sword, and much more. </p><p>If you don&apos;t have the Nintendo Music app, then head to the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/nintendo-music/id6466376604?ref=retrododo.com">App Store</a> or <a href="https://play.google.com/store/search?q=nintendo+music&amp;c=apps&amp;hl=en&amp;ref=retrododo.com">Google Play</a> to get in on the action. Now, where did I put my Hylian Shield? </p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Forgotten Atari Lynx Fighting Game Being Revived By Songbird Productions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Songbird Productions first acquired the rights to the 90s Atari Lynx game Ultravortek 25 years ago, back in the year 2000; talk about sitting on a project for a while and taking the time to get it right! </p><p>Ultravortek&apos;s story is a bittersweet one; it began its life</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/forgotten-atari-lynx-fighting-game-being-revived-by-songbird-productions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681b80a19202b10001ce93d1</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:04:44 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/ultravore-lynx.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/ultravore-lynx.jpg" alt="Forgotten Atari Lynx Fighting Game Being Revived By Songbird Productions"><p>Songbird Productions first acquired the rights to the 90s Atari Lynx game Ultravortek 25 years ago, back in the year 2000; talk about sitting on a project for a while and taking the time to get it right! </p><p>Ultravortek&apos;s story is a bittersweet one; it began its life being created by Beyond Games in 1990 as UltraVortek for the Atari Jaguar and, after a series of missed deadlines and poor reception from the public, didn&apos;t exactly go on to greatness. It was supposed to see a release for the Lynx, but because of the reasons listed above it sadly never happened. </p><p>Now that Songbird have all the rights and the entire source code and assets from the game (I say now, more like &apos;now that they&apos;ve had it for a quarter of a century&apos;), they&apos;re planning on re-releasing UltraVortek as UltraVore, and they&apos;re planning some cool enhancements to bring the game into this decade. </p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here is the first-ever video capture of Ultravore for the Atari Lynx. Enjoy! <br><br>Read the&#x1F9F5;below to learn about the history of the game, and what&apos;s coming next.<a href="https://t.co/Lu4646v3sG?ref=retrododo.com">https://t.co/Lu4646v3sG</a></p>&#x2014; Songbird Productions &#x1F195; Old Towers for the Jaguar (@SongbirdPro) <a href="https://twitter.com/SongbirdPro/status/1919916302254084215?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=retrododo.com">May 7, 2025</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>According to the official Songbird Productions X page, the team has said <em>&quot;We&apos;ve already added health bars, variable damage depending on the move, new graphics, and new audio. Other possible features include music, multiple environments, more fighters, etc. More enhancements means a lot more work, so we may look at a crowdfunding option to broaden the scope beyond necessary upgrades. We want to deliver a fantastic fighting game for Lynx fans.&quot;<strong> </strong></em></p><p>The tweet ends with the news &apos;Coming soon... when we&apos;re done with it&apos;, so I wouldn&apos;t expect it any time soon! Still, you can check out the video posted by Songbird featuring never-before-seen footage of the game below to get yourself hyped up for when it does release! (Thanks to <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/05/lost-atari-lynx-fighting-game-ultravore-is-being-revived-25-years-after-its-rights-were-acquired?ref=retrododo.com">Time Extension</a> for the heads up!). </p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MheMgL__LMI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Ultravore for the Atari Lynx teaser"></iframe></figure><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ANBERNIC Announce RG34XXSP Clamshell With Dual Joysticks]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&apos;ve sung the praises of the RG35XXSP over the past year; it&apos;s still one of my main go-to clamshell handhelds and one that I send other people to purchase if they&apos;re looking for a reliable handheld for those old-school GBA SP vibes.</p><p>We gave</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/anbernic-announce-rg34xxsp-clamshell-with-dual-joysticks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681b2e589202b10001ce9311</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 11:04:50 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/rg34xxsp.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/rg34xxsp.jpg" alt="ANBERNIC Announce RG34XXSP Clamshell With Dual Joysticks"><p>I&apos;ve sung the praises of the RG35XXSP over the past year; it&apos;s still one of my main go-to clamshell handhelds and one that I send other people to purchase if they&apos;re looking for a reliable handheld for those old-school GBA SP vibes.</p><p>We gave it <a href="https://retrododo.com/anbernic-rg35xxsp-review/" rel="noreferrer">9 out of 10</a> in our dedicated, in-depth review and branded it as one of the best consoles to play GBA games on, apart from the <a href="https://retrododo.com/anbernic-rg34xx-review/" rel="noreferrer">RG34XX GBA clone</a>, but now Anbernic have brought out a new iteration in the RG34XXSP, just to confuse you even more. </p><p>The new RG34XXSP looks exactly like the original RG35XXSP, apart from the addition of two joysticks at the bottom of the console, effectively making it look like the <a href="https://retrododo.com/miyoo-flip-pre-orders-are-finally-open-to-more-people/" rel="noreferrer">Miyoo Flip</a>. I say effectively, it&apos;s pretty much identical.</p><p>This is typical ANBERNIC fashion as they have a long history of emulating other consoles that do well, sometimes faster than the original can launch, due to the sheer size of their company. It&apos;s classic spray and pray to see what sticks, and we&apos;ve said before, it&apos;s usually 1 in 10 of their products that we love - the rest are very mediocre.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/rg34xxsp-colours-1.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="ANBERNIC Announce RG34XXSP Clamshell With Dual Joysticks" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/rg34xxsp-colours-1.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/rg34xxsp-colours-1.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/rg34xxsp-colours-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Credit: ANBERNIC</span></figcaption></figure><p>You all know how I feel about adding joysticks onto handhelds like this, especially when they&apos;re crammed so close to the bottom of the casing that you have to hold it like an octopus. But if I&apos;m remaining objective, it will make playing PS1 and PSP games much easier without having to head into RetroArch and remapping the D-pad to Joystick controls. It works fine for N64 titles, but for games like God of War and Resident Evil, the gameplay flows much better with joysticks. </p><p>I&apos;m getting ahead of myself, let&apos;s take a look at some of the stats of the RG34XXSP and compare them to the RG35XXSP. </p><p>The RG35XXSP has a 3.5 IPS display with a 640x480 resolution, whereas the RG34XXSP has a 3.4-inch full-fit IPS screen with a resolution of 720x480. ANBERNIC state that it provides a &apos;perfect 3x pixel-to-pixel experience when playing GBA games&apos;, something I can fully get behind. It looks like a GBA SP, after all, so that&apos;s the least that you would expect from it. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P2sOzyP2hlc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="ANBERNIC RG 34XXSP Classic Fun Games&amp; Expansion Features Showcase"></iframe></figure><p>When it comes to WiFi and Bluetooth, the RG34XXSP boasts a 5G WiFi module and supports WiliWili online playback. It can also enable Moonlight streaming for playing AAA titles on the handheld as well as accessing WiFi multiplayer features. </p><p>It&apos;s technically an upgrade to the RG35XXSP, but the screen isn&apos;t going to be great for playing AAA widescreen titles on it, so it seems like an unnecessary addition, in my opinion. I wouldn&apos;t buy this console to play games like Shredder&apos;s Revenge even though it boasts that it can play it in the official press release - I&apos;d save that for a horizontal handheld like the <a href="https://retrododo.com/anbernic-rg406h-review/">RG406H</a>. The RG34XXSP does have the option to HDMI out to a TV and hook up Bluetooth controllers, but still, I wouldn&apos;t really think about using this for anything more than PS1 gameplay, so I still don&apos;t think I would use that function that often when I have other handhelds that can also do the same thing. </p><p>I don&apos;t have any information on the CPU, GPU, or RAM in the RG34XXSP yet, but I&apos;m hoping that information will be heading over soon. One thing I can get excited about, however, is the new colours. That purple with the SNES coloured buttons is very slick, and I&apos;m a big fan of the Volt yellow colourway too. </p><p>But are they enough for me to want to part with my cash when I already own the RG35XXSP, though? This handheld will have to seriously blow me away with its performance in order to change my mind, and I&apos;m already coming into it with a hatred of those joysticks. Keep your eyes peeled for more updates right here as and when I get more information!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lpICGjV_Jnw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="ANBERNIC RG35XXSP: The Perfect Affordable Handheld?"></iframe></figure><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Atari & Limited Run Games Announce 'Bubsy In: The Purrfect Collection']]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In normal life, I&apos;m a dog person, but when it comes to video games, I&apos;ve got a real soft spot for Bubsy the Cat. A new collection of his past games is coming to Switch, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, PC, and Steam after being announced</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/atari-limited-run-games-announce-bubsy-in-the-purrfect-collection/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681a40859202b10001ce9284</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 17:21:05 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/busby.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/busby.jpg" alt="Atari &amp; Limited Run Games Announce &apos;Bubsy In: The Purrfect Collection&apos;"><p>In normal life, I&apos;m a dog person, but when it comes to video games, I&apos;ve got a real soft spot for Bubsy the Cat. A new collection of his past games is coming to Switch, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, PC, and Steam after being announced by Atari and Limited Run Games. It&apos;s called the Purrfect Collection (genius) and will feature games from the Atari Jaguar through to the PS1. </p><p>Check out the full list below - </p><ul><li><strong><em>Bubsy in Fractured Furry Tales</em></strong>&#xA0;(Atari Jaguar)</li><li><strong><em>Bubsy in Claws Encounters of the Furred Kind</em></strong>&#xA0;(SEGA Genesis, Super Nintendo, Super Famicon)</li><li><strong><em>Bubsy II</em></strong>&#xA0;(Game Boy, Sega Genesis, Super Nintendo)</li><li><strong><em>Bubsy 3D</em></strong>&#xA0;(PlayStation)</li></ul><p>In a similar vein to the Crocipedia on the new <a href="https://retrododo.com/croc-legend-of-the-gobbos-remastered-review/" rel="noreferrer">Croc: Legend of the Gobbos remaster</a>, the collection has artifacts and interviews that give gamers a better insight into how the games were made. All eight of the titles in the collection (titles for different systems are included as per the list above) have had modern enhancements to bring them kicking and screaming into this decade, but they still stay true to the original Bubsy formula. </p><p>Atari even managed to get us a direct quote from Bubsy himself - <em>&#x201C;Here we go again! I&#x2019;m pawsitively pumped to bring my collection of purrfectly preserved pixels to cool cats everywhere. Hold onto your whiskers and get ready for a glide down memory lane, polished and pampered for your playing pleasure. What could possibly go wrong?&#x201D;</em></p><p>As of right now, I don&apos;t have any solid release dates to give you, but in the meantime, you can <a href="https://urals.co/atari/bubsycollection?ref=retrododo.com">head to Atari</a> to find out more about the upcoming collection or <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3039890/Bubsy_in_The_Purrfect_Collection/?ref=retrododo.com">wishlist it on Steam</a>!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pizza Pop! Is Finally Coming To The NES Worldwide Over Three Decades Later]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If I see anything related to pizza, I get excited. It&apos;s part of the curse of being Italian, along with always being hungry for pasta. If you&apos;re into your Famicom history, then you&apos;ll no doubt know about this hidden gem that only ever dropped</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/pizza-pop-is-finally-coming-to-the-nes-worldwide-over-three-decades-later/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681a2aec9202b10001ce923a</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:04:53 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pizza-pops.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pizza-pops.jpg" alt="Pizza Pop! Is Finally Coming To The NES Worldwide Over Three Decades Later"><p>If I see anything related to pizza, I get excited. It&apos;s part of the curse of being Italian, along with always being hungry for pasta. If you&apos;re into your Famicom history, then you&apos;ll no doubt know about this hidden gem that only ever dropped in Japan. Released by Jaleco in 1992, it&apos;s a story about a small American town and a kid called Kid (imaginative, I know) who wants to surprise his girl Betty with a ring. And do you know how he&apos;s gonna save up for it? By delivering pizza, of course!</p><p>33 years later, there&apos;s now an English translation of the game available to purchase and play on the NES. Yes, an actual physical cartridge for you to stop your rival Nick from stealing your girl across seven stages + bonus levels, working around the clock to treat Betty to a $10,000 ring. </p><p>Wait... $10,000! That&apos;s going to be a lot of deliveries!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vjkR6T9BPa0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Jaleco Game Release - Pizza Pop!"></iframe></figure><p>The translation and gameplay enhancements have been a joint effort of City Connection, Omak&#xE9; Games, Broke Studio, and <a href="https://upsilandre.over-blog.com/?ref=retrododo.com">Upsilandre</a>. The game, which comes with a physical cartridge, cartridge sleeve, colour box, manual, styrofoam block, and a flyer, costs &#x20AC;50 and is <a href="https://www.homebrew-factory.com/home/143-pizza-pop-nes.html?ref=retrododo.com">available to purchase now</a>. The first 100 orders will receive a limited edition Pizza Pop! pin, and one lucky buyer will receive a gold cartridge. Mamma Mia!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Officially Licensed Abe Action Figure Is Making Waves Over On Kickstarter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Of all the PS1 characters from our youth, Abe stands out in our minds as being one of the weirdest. Don&apos;t get me wrong, he&apos;s also one of the most iconic and influential, but one of the weirdest nonetheless. He certainly left an impression on our</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/this-officially-licensed-abe-action-figure-is-making-waves-over-on-kickstarter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">681a01a89202b10001ce91c4</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:05:02 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/abe-action-figure.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/abe-action-figure.jpg" alt="This Officially Licensed Abe Action Figure Is Making Waves Over On Kickstarter"><p>Of all the PS1 characters from our youth, Abe stands out in our minds as being one of the weirdest. Don&apos;t get me wrong, he&apos;s also one of the most iconic and influential, but one of the weirdest nonetheless. He certainly left an impression on our video editor Rob, who has <a href="https://retrododo.com/best-oddworld-games/" rel="noreferrer">collected multiple versions of the same game</a> in homage to Oddworld&apos;s saviour. And now, you can have a constant reminder of Abe&apos;s Oddysee (and the odyssey he&apos;s left behind) sitting next to your computer thanks to this blast-from-the-past Kickstarter. </p><p>UK studio Gametee have been working on an officially licensed 5&quot; action figure of Abe, and it looks so real that he could have jumped straight out of your TV  back in 1997. It has 10 points of articulation and can be adjusted into some of Abe&apos;s most iconic poses. Gametee say that it&apos;s made for maximum playability, so Brandon will probably get his young son to put that to the test!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Abe-figure.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="This Officially Licensed Abe Action Figure Is Making Waves Over On Kickstarter" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Abe-figure.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Abe-figure.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Abe-figure.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Credit: Gametee</span></figcaption></figure><p>The attention to detail in this figurine is wild - the textures and tone on Abe&apos;s skin are perfect, as is the packaging too, created using the <em>&apos;authentic Abe&apos;s Oddysee Art and Promotional files from 1997, embellished with authentic details from the game.&apos; </em></p><p>This action figure, officially licensed by Oddworld Inhabitants, is supremely Limited Edition - when they&apos;re gone, they&apos;re gone, and the only way to get hold of one is through the official <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gametee/abe-officially-licensed-5-inch-articulated-action-figure?ref=discovery_newest&amp;term=retro&amp;total_hits=7548&amp;category_id=35">Kickstarter Campaign</a>. One figure costs &#xA3;28, and you can grab an awesome T-shirt for &#xA3;24 too. Honestly, I think &#xA3;28 for an officially licensed collectible is incredibly reasonable; let us know in the comments if you&apos;ll be putting your name down for one!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Wii U Concept Is The Next Mini Console Nintendo Should Develop]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I think we can all agree that the Wii U was a bit of a flop, but that doesn&apos;t mean that it wasn&apos;t a great console. After all, it&apos;s the original home of Mario Kart 8, and you can pick up a Wii U</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/this-wii-u-concept-is-the-next-mini-console-nintendo-should-develop/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6819f3089202b10001ce916d</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 11:58:19 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/wii-u-concept-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/wii-u-concept-1.jpg" alt="This Wii U Concept Is The Next Mini Console Nintendo Should Develop"><p>I think we can all agree that the Wii U was a bit of a flop, but that doesn&apos;t mean that it wasn&apos;t a great console. After all, it&apos;s the original home of Mario Kart 8, and you can pick up a Wii U copy of Breath of the Wild for very cheap these days. What&apos;s more, it&apos;s the last console to have HD versions of The Wind Waker and Twilight Princess in physical form. It was an important step in creating the Nintendo Switch, but apart from the god awful name, the design just wasn&apos;t cool or ergonomic. </p><p>Well, Nintendo, sit up and take a look at this concept design from <a href="https://www.coroflot.com/BSullivan/WiiU-Gamepad-Redesign?ref=retrododo.com">Brendan Sullivan</a>, because it turns the massive plastic handheld of yesteryear into a sleek handheld that would provide retro gaming fans a chance to relive Wii U titles on the go, or even at home if it came with a mini HDMI out like <a href="https://retrododo.com/helegaly-a527-review/">Helegaly Action &#x3C0;</a> or the CRKD Nitro Deck Plus.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Wii-u-Concept-3.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="This Wii U Concept Is The Next Mini Console Nintendo Should Develop" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/Wii-u-Concept-3.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/Wii-u-Concept-3.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/Wii-u-Concept-3.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Credit: Brendan Sullivan</span></figcaption></figure><p>Tell me you wouldn&apos;t buy one of these WiiboyU handhelds if they became available? For me, this is so much cooler than the Switch Lite and manages to implement that retro Game &amp; Watch meets Nintendo DS-style shape into a powerful console that can handle the likes of BotW and Yoshi&apos;s Wooly World. It looks more like a handheld and less like a toy, which is exactly how the Wii U Gamepad looked and felt. </p><p>A handheld that came pre-loaded with classic Wii and Wii U games, or with a store for you to purchase your favourites to play offline - that would be the dream. And yes, if GameCube is coming to Nintendo Switch online once the new console drops, then there&apos;s a chance that Wii games might also appear their soon, but a handheld Wii U would no doubt come in at a fraction of the price of the new Switch, and we&apos;d all pick one up regardless. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/wii-u-concept-2.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="This Wii U Concept Is The Next Mini Console Nintendo Should Develop" loading="lazy" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/wii-u-concept-2.jpg 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/wii-u-concept-2.jpg 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/wii-u-concept-2.jpg 1280w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">Credit: Brendan Sullivan</span></figcaption></figure><p>Imagine a world where Nintendo suddenly became the makers of one of the best retro handhelds, if they didn&apos;t need to sue emulator makers or battle the likes of AYANEO or ANBERNIC for affordable handhelds that play games for their later consoles because they had made one themselves, one that looked modern and slick like Brendan&apos;as design. Many of the comments we get asking about which is the best emulator are for people looking to play Wii and Wii U games, so if Nintendo just gave the public what they want in a handheld that shipped under $180 which played games flawlessly, it would solve a lot of their issues. </p><p>Still, Brendan&apos;s WiiboyU design remains a concept for now, though if Nintendo decide to take note or if someone makes a move to create something similar, I&apos;ll be the first to part with my hard-earned cash to give it a try. </p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nintendo 3DS Audio Guides Are Soon Leaving The Louvre]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The video of Satoru Iwata and Shigeru Miyamoto going round the Louvre in Paris with 3DS guides lives rent-free in my brain. To see these two legendary figures in the gaming world walking around one of the most prestigious museums on the planet laughing and joking while using their handheld</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/nintendo-3ds-audio-guides-are-soon-leaving-the-louvre/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6819e3599202b10001ce9138</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 10:48:11 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/shigeru-3ds.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/shigeru-3ds.jpg" alt="Nintendo 3DS Audio Guides Are Soon Leaving The Louvre"><p>The video of Satoru Iwata and Shigeru Miyamoto going round the Louvre in Paris with 3DS guides lives rent-free in my brain. To see these two legendary figures in the gaming world walking around one of the most prestigious museums on the planet laughing and joking while using their handheld to learn about art could well be one of the most wholesome videos in Nintendo history, and the 3DS has been helping people learn more about art and culture in minute detail since the Louvre started using the technology back in 2012. </p><p>For &#x20AC;6, visitors could rent a 3DS to take it around with them for an audio guide of the museum in either English, French, Spanish, Italian, Portuguese, German, Japanese, Korean, or Chinese (<a href="https://www.engadget.com/gaming/nintendo/the-louvre-will-stop-renting-out-nintendo-3ds-audio-guides-in-september-150057520.html?ref=retrododo.com">thanks Endgadget</a> for the language rundown). Not only that, but those who rented a handheld could learn about the history of the Louvre itself as well as zoom in on tiny details of digital versions of the artwork in front of them to better understand how they were made and fully immerse themselves in their brilliance. They also have a geo-tracking feature to help you find out where you are, like the &apos;you are here&apos; arrow on a map in a shopping mall. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WavLP_3ew-A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Nintendo Direct - Nintendo 3DS Guide: Louvre"></iframe></figure><p>All that is about to change, however, as after 13 years of loyal service, the Louvre is ditching the 3DS audio guide in favour of a new system. I wonder if they&apos;re suddenly going to get a bundle of Nintendo Switch Lites now that the Switch 2 is coming out or if they&apos;re going to go back to a traditional audio guide route. All that we know is that there&apos;s a notice on the <a href="https://www.louvre.fr/en/visit/visitor-amenities?ref=retrododo.com">official Louvre website</a> stating that the 3DS audio guides will &apos;go out of operation in 2025.&apos; So, if you still want to have the same kind of fun as Iwata and Miyamoto in the video above, then get over to Paris right away - you&apos;ve got 3 months before they disappear!</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ecco The Dolphin & The Tides Of Time To Be Remastered + A 3rd New Game On The Way]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Classic Sega Game Ecco the Dolphin and its sequel The Tides of Time are getting brand new remasters according to Ecco&apos;s creator Ed Annunziata. Speaking with <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/xbox-asian-pacific-islander-heritage-month-2025/?ref=retrododo.com">Xbox Wire</a> about ocean preservation during an interview celebrating Asian and Pacific Islander Heritage Month, Ed spoke about how Ecco had not</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/ecco-the-dolphin-the-tides-of-time-to-be-remastered-a-3rd-new-game-on-the-way/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6819c5369202b10001ce90cc</guid><category><![CDATA[News]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Santabarbara]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:52:14 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/ecco.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/ecco.jpg" alt="Ecco The Dolphin &amp; The Tides Of Time To Be Remastered + A 3rd New Game On The Way"><p>Classic Sega Game Ecco the Dolphin and its sequel The Tides of Time are getting brand new remasters according to Ecco&apos;s creator Ed Annunziata. Speaking with <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/05/05/xbox-asian-pacific-islander-heritage-month-2025/?ref=retrododo.com">Xbox Wire</a> about ocean preservation during an interview celebrating Asian and Pacific Islander Heritage Month, Ed spoke about how Ecco had not just become a recognisable and beloved character for millions of gamers across the globe, but how this little Dolphin had helped us all to think more carefully about protecting our oceans. </p><p>Ed states that gamers have a higher IQ than most humans, something that I can definitely get behind. And he&apos;s channeled this thought into the Ecco games, much like with his incredibly smart dolphin characters. <em>&apos;Like the ocean, a gaming community is an ecosystem &#x2013; games like Ecco can and should be a conduit to join these realms. A big part of the game is understanding the ocean as a singular biological system that is made up of systems that interact with each other. This is a complex biological dance that humans can be a part of.&apos;&#xA0;</em></p><p>When asked what the future holds for Ecco, Ed gave some incredible news that old Mega Drive/Genesis fans like me have been waiting to hear for years. He and the entire team that worked on the original Ecco the Dolphin game are going to remaster both Ecco the Dolphin and Sega CD game The Tides of Time for new audiences, as well as a brand new third title that they&apos;ll be working on that we don&apos;t have any information about yet. </p><p>It&apos;s been 32 years since The Tides of Time released on the Sega CD, and while we&apos;ve had other Ecco games since with the last dropping on the Dreamcast in 2000, it&apos;s definitely time for a whole new generation of gamers to discover Ecco and find out more about the world under the waves in the process. There&apos;s currently a timer counting down the hours, minutes, and seconds to when the remasters will release - as I write this line, it&apos;s currently on 354 days and 27 minutes, so we&apos;ve got around a year till next May to wait until Ecco returns. You can keep tabs on the timer at <a href="https://nam06.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eccothedolphin.com%2F&amp;data=05%7C02%7Cv-kbalough%40microsoft.com%7Ce0d535b16bac4b4b5b3808dd891524ae%7C72f988bf86f141af91ab2d7cd011db47%7C1%7C0%7C638817446095116526%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJFbXB0eU1hcGkiOnRydWUsIlYiOiIwLjAuMDAwMCIsIlAiOiJXaW4zMiIsIkFOIjoiTWFpbCIsIldUIjoyfQ%3D%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=nwG3r%2BKO%2Fppkh4QBNorVp6KuJRXlggD%2FCbB1Fzuiq4E%3D&amp;reserved=0&amp;ref=retrododo.com">eccothedolphin.com</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finding One Of The UK's Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>My local retro games shop here in the UK is annoyingly hidden in the back of a popular music store in Swindon, as if it&apos;s secret, or only known by &quot;locals&quot;. This is mostly due to the fact that it has no shopfront, so you could</p>]]></description><link>https://retrododo.com/finding-one-of-the-uks-best-retro-game-shops-hidden-in-a-music-store/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">68175f9c0622b500017f0f7a</guid><category><![CDATA[Originals]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Saltalamacchia]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 19:51:16 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/swindon-retro-games-hq.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/swindon-retro-games-hq.jpg" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?"><p>My local retro games shop here in the UK is annoyingly hidden in the back of a popular music store in Swindon, as if it&apos;s secret, or only known by &quot;locals&quot;. This is mostly due to the fact that it has no shopfront, so you could walk right by one of the UK&apos;s best games collections and not even know it.</p><p>But once you find this place, or an awesome independent publication shines light on it (hint hint) you&apos;ll be amazed at what you&apos;ll find, and you&apos;ll be greeted with a lovely chap named Pete who has been in the gaming retail business for 30 years.</p><p><a href="https://retrogames-swindon.co.uk/?ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer">Retro Games HQ</a> is located in Swindon&apos;s high street, tucked behind the guitars, drums and keyboards of the store Holmes Music, ran by Pete&apos;s father.</p><p><strong><em>We created a whole 30 minute tour and introduction video to partner with this article, and I believe it&apos;s the best way to see what this magical gem has to offer, feel free to watch it below and </em></strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@RetroDodo?ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer"><strong><em>subscribe to the channel</em></strong></a><strong><em> to see more </em></strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLtX-eXzePbzdYaThoWoIUz4BeTACO_mw0&amp;ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer"><strong><em>The Retroad Show</em></strong></a><strong><em> episodes.</em></strong></p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/loQNDNn1ZKQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Inside The UK&apos;s Most HIDDEN Retro Games Shop"></iframe></figure><h2 id="the-owner-pete-holmes">The Owner, Pete Holmes</h2><p>Pete Holmes is the owner of the store and will likely greet you as soon as you step foot into his retro games section of the music store, at times appearing out of thin air to assist with your collection needs and questions.</p><p>Pete has been collecting for many years, likely thanks to his father who would return from Japan on business trips with a treat or two, usually in the form of unique <a href="https://retrododo.com/best-game-watch-games/" rel="noreferrer">Game &amp; Watch consoles</a>. Pete&apos;s most vivid Game &amp; Watch was the Donkey Kong edition.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pete-holmes-retro-gamez-hq.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/pete-holmes-retro-gamez-hq.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/pete-holmes-retro-gamez-hq.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/pete-holmes-retro-gamez-hq.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pete-holmes-retro-gamez-hq.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><em>&quot;My dad started the music shop, Holmes Music, back in the late 60s. He&apos;s been open 60 years now, so retail is in my blood&quot; states Pete. I got a bit fed up with the music side of things, and my passion was video games. So I started off by importing Super Nintendo Mega Drive games from Japan and America.</em></p><p><em>Street Fighter would come out in Japan first, then 6 months later America, and then finally hit the UK. So we skipped that, went direct to Japan, ordered copies of things like Street Fighter or the latest games with the use of converters on Super Nintendos as well as importing the consoles as well&quot;.</em></p><p><em>We get people come in  downstairs and they&apos;re going &quot;Wow, what a collection you got here. I just mention &quot;Have you been in before?&quot;... &quot;No, no, this is my first time.&quot; And I say &quot;Oh, you need to go upstairs and have a look.&quot; And then they go up upstairs and the phones come out, everybody&apos;s taking pictures, videos, sending them to their friends, and it&apos;s like &quot;Wow, we didn&apos;t expect this!&quot;</em></p><p>I have personally known Pete for a few years now, and often make my way into the store when I pass through Swindon and he informed me that he could have rented shop space elsewhere but his father had the music store, and the both decided to expand the space internally on both the ground floor and the second floor to make space for more business and Pete&apos;s game collection.</p><div class="kg-card kg-header-card kg-v2 kg-layout-split kg-width-full kg-style-accent" data-background-color="accent">
            
            <div class="kg-header-card-content">
                
            <picture><img class="kg-header-card-image" src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pete-retro-2.webp" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/pete-retro-2.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/pete-retro-2.webp 943w" loading="lazy" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?"></picture>
        
                <div class="kg-header-card-text ">
                    <h2 id="we-literally-have-people-travel-from-all-over-the-world-to-visit-us-weve-had-a-lot-of-visitors-on-holiday-from-australia-america-japan-that-are-up-in-london-find-us-on-the-internet-and-jump-on-the-train-to-visit" class="kg-header-card-heading" style="color: #FFFFFF;" data-text-color="#FFFFFF"><b><strong style="white-space: pre-wrap;">We literally have people travel from all over the world to visit us. We&apos;ve had a lot of visitors on holiday from Australia, America, Japan that are up in London, find us on the internet and jump on the train to visit.</strong></b></h2>
                    <p id="-pete-holmes" class="kg-header-card-subheading" style="color: #FFFFFF;" data-text-color="#FFFFFF"><span style="white-space: pre-wrap;">- Pete Holmes</span></p>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div><h2 id="the-ground-floorjapanese-esque-and-overwhelming-nostalgia">The Ground Floor - Japanese-esque and Overwhelming Nostalgia</h2><p>The ground floor in itself is what I would class as a &quot;typical&quot; retro games store here in the UK, small with an array of choices to gander at, from SEGA Mega Drive games/consoles, to rare 90&apos;s gaming statues, to loose Demo PS1 discs only found in vintage gaming magazines and an array of loose carts for Nintendo consoles.</p><p>Retro game stores are niche here in the UK, and in themselves struggle to survive the high tax bills and low foot fall due to it being niche and typically &quot;expensive&quot; in the eyes of traditional consumers. That&apos;s why many are &quot;small&quot;, for example <a href="https://retrododo.com/inside-super-tomato/" rel="noreferrer">Super Tomato in Cardiff</a> that also shared the struggle with running the business, the same goes for <a href="https://retrododo.com/inside-retro-sect-the-uks-hidden-gem-retro-games-store/" rel="noreferrer">Retro-sect in Tewkesbury</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-ground-level.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-ground-level.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/retro-games-hq-ground-level.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-ground-level.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-ground-level.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>It feels like a Japanese video game store, jam packed from floor to ceiling, with rare boxed consoles spilling out onto the floor hoping customers don&apos;t stand on them, but it&apos;s the only place Pete has for them otherwise it would take up precious space in the music section which, I presume would start an all out war with his father, and nobody wants that... we know what Dads can be like!</p><p>One of the many gems I found on the ground floor was Spud&apos;s Adventure and Amazing Tater, two of the <a href="https://retrododo.com/rare-gameboy-games/" rel="noreferrer">rarest Game Boy games</a> ever made, alongside rare Nintendo Watches from the 80s/90&apos;s including Zelda.</p><p>The closer you look, the more you will see on this level, from unique accessories to fully boxed consoles, to PS Vita games to pop culture collectibles scattered around.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-downstairs-2.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-downstairs-2.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-downstairs-2.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-downstairs-2.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-downstairs-2.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Pete also labels the loose carts to make it easier to pick out, alongside pricing on every single product... He&apos;s a mad man, but it makes it easier for customers to pick up things and bring them to checkout.</p><p>The higher end products are behind glass cabinets due to Pete having customers steal his products on a frequent basis, which is a shame as he, like any small business owner is simply trying to mix passion with putting food on the table for his family.</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> ,<a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a> or checking out <a href="https://retrododo.myshopify.com/?ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer"><b><strong style="white-space: pre-wrap;">our store</strong></b></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div><h2 id="the-second-floorspace-for-retro-exploration">The Second Floor - Space For Retro Exploration</h2><p>The second floor has much more space, and likely double or triple the product to explore. What I like about this level is that there&apos;s places to sit, to read vintage gaming magazines, and even a couple of arcade cabinets for you to lose half an hour in, making it a great location to waste a couple of hours while your partner shops on the high street.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-upstairs-2.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-upstairs-2.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-upstairs-2.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-upstairs-2.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-swindon-upstairs-2.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>And that&apos;s what Pete is trying to build, a unique store that becomes an experience, all thanks to the way it&apos;s designed and how the inventory is laid out. </p><p>On the second floor, once you pass the collection of retro posters on the way up you will find a cabinet dedicated to boxed and unboxed Game Boy Advance games, hundreds of them.</p><p>Next to that a incredibly rare XBOX 360 retail cabinet, the very ones used in stores to test the consoles and games upon release. Then there&apos;s the long line of cabinets filled with so much Nintendo gear that it rivals <a href="https://youtu.be/T2WD8KEQ9iw?si=PTYPvS-OvEqA36y0&amp;ref=retrododo.com" rel="noreferrer">Don&apos;s collection from our previous episode</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-3.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-3.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-3.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-3.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-3.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>You&apos;ll find Nintendo 64 consoles boxed, rare accessories for the Nintendo Wii, sealed Gamecube games, some of the rarest NES games I have ever seen and a scattering of Japanese imports.</p><p>Swinging around to the back you&apos;ll find lots of Skylanders, pins, Nintendo Wii games, and even a 5ft tall Nintendo Zelda Watch that has a screen with ROMs installed, to be used as its very own games machine.</p><p>Then... my favourite part, the Game Boy section, an array of consoles in various editions, some needing repairs but most ready to play, some even coming with the box. Pete has a large Game Boy game collection too, with some rare Castlevania games, Pokemon games and well over 50 boxed games ready to go too.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-4.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-4.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-4.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-4.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/retro-games-hq-upstairs-4.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Heck I even found a boxed HANDY BOY for the original DMG that I just had to take home with me, alongside GAME BOY carry cases that I wanted to snag but at some point I had to tell myself no... and by myself I mean my bank.</p><h2 id="a-must-visit-for-any-retro-gaming-enthusiast-down-south">A must visit for any retro gaming enthusiast down south.</h2><p>The Retro Gamez HQ is one of the last standing retro game shops in the UK, unfortunately as most of us know, there&apos;s not many left. It&apos;s obvious hearing Pete&apos;s story that he has been through the trenches trying to keep this store alive for as long as he can.</p><p>He&apos;s still swinging, even amongst the battle scars, and he does it with a happy face and a good professional attitude. He tries his best to do what he can for both customers buying stock and curious gamers wanting to sell their collection.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/brandon-retro-games-hq.webp" class="kg-image" alt="Finding One Of The UK&apos;s Best Retro Game Shops... Hidden In A Music Store?" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w600/2025/05/brandon-retro-games-hq.webp 600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1000/2025/05/brandon-retro-games-hq.webp 1000w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/size/w1600/2025/05/brandon-retro-games-hq.webp 1600w, https://retrododo.com/content/images/2025/05/brandon-retro-games-hq.webp 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>He&apos;s passionate, turns up every day to graft for his customers and has created a unique store that i can&apos;t help but visit every few months. He understands the struggles and opportunities that a retail store brings, and I believe he will continue to keep the doors open for as long as he can for his community.</p><p>It&apos;s one of the main reasons why I try to buy from independent gaming stores like this, purely because of passion. They need our help the most and I fear the day that they all close. None of us want the only place to buy retro games to be online or from a mainstream games shop with no passion.</p><p>If you are in the South of the UK, give Pete a visit. I am very confident that you won&apos;t be disappointed with what you see, it&apos;s one of the best retro game shops in the UK.</p><div class="kg-card kg-callout-card kg-callout-card-purple"><div class="kg-callout-emoji">&#x2764;&#xFE0F;</div><div class="kg-callout-text">Like what you are reading? If you do and want to support us, you can do so by <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">becoming a member</strong></b></u></a> or <a href="https://retrododo.com/#/portal/support" rel="noreferrer"><u><b><strong class="underline" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">tipping us</strong></b></u></a>! This allows us to continue what we do without succumbing to algorithms, click-bait and over-intrusive ads, while paying human writers instead of AI.</div></div>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>