<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>WatchTime &#8211; USA&#039;s No.1 Watch Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.watchtime.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.watchtime.com</link>
	<description>Wristwatch reviews, watch news, watch database.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:10:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/WatchTime_Icon-205x205.jpg</url>
	<title>WatchTime &#8211; USA&#039;s No.1 Watch Magazine</title>
	<link>https://www.watchtime.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Up Close With the Grand Seiko Hi-Beat 36,000 GMT 44GS 55th Anniversary</title>
		<link>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/up-close-with-the-grand-seiko-hi-beat-36000-gmt-44gs-55th-anniversary/</link>
					<comments>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/up-close-with-the-grand-seiko-hi-beat-36000-gmt-44gs-55th-anniversary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Krupp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Seiko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Limited Edition Watches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watch Tests]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.watchtime.com/?p=145028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A white,&#160;finely structured dial, faceted hands, applied indexes and an almost entirely polished case: these features are familiar in elegant dress watches that look good but do little else than show the time. What happens if a watch ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A white,&nbsp;finely structured dial, faceted hands, applied indexes and an almost entirely polished case: these features are familiar in elegant dress watches that look good but do little else than show the time. What happens if a watch manufacturer wants to combine these classic properties with functional features, and also wants to equip the new creation with additional functions and a robust exterior? Is it possible to build a watch that not only appeals to a client’s eye, but also to his insistence on a high degree of usability in daily life?</p>



<p>It is indeed possible, but only if you get everything right. And that’s exactly what Grand Seiko has done with its Hi-Beat 36000 GMT 44GS 55th Anniversary Limited Edition, our test watch, which was introduced in January 2022. The name refers to the 44GS, launched 55 years ago, whose handsomely shaped case serves as the model for this new Grand Seiko’s design. This new watch not only looks elegant, but also offers a high level of everyday usability: for example, in addition to a perfectly located date display, the Japanese manufacturer also has added a 24-hour hand with a corresponding scale around the edge of the dial.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/44b9857e1dc4d1d48998.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-145029"/></figure>



<p>The additional function is so cleverly integrated that it’s hard to imagine this timepiece without it — not to mention the function’s usefulness: if you cross a time zone boundary, you simply pull the crown out to its first position and rotate it to propel the main hour hand forward or backward in one-hour increments. At midnight, the date jumps forward or backward as necessary, as you would expect from a travel watch. The blue hand stoically remains in its original position to show the time in your home time zone throughout the journey. Those who prefer to stay at home will appreciate the quick adjustment for the hour hand, which makes it easy to switch between daylight saving time and standard time because the movement continues to run, thus preserving the correctness of the minute and second.</p>



<p>But that’s by no means the end of this watch’s functional features. Grand Seiko also includes its in-house luminous material called Lumibrite. This luminous substance is nearly unnoticeable during the day, but effectively illuminates three of the four hands and all 11 hour markers at night.</p>



<p>And then there’s the choice of material — titanium, which gives this new Grand Seiko an advantage over pure dress watches. The case and bracelet are made of this robust but lightweight metal, although all the polished parts look more like stainless steel. And this appearance is intentional. To achieve it, the manufactory created its own high-intensity titanium alloy. The alloy’s uncommon hardness exceeds that of conventional titanium and makes it possible to apply Grand Seiko’s characteristic “Zaratsu” polishing, which results in especially smooth and distortion-free reflective surfaces that shine as brightly as stainless steel.</p>



<p>Titanium also considerably reduces weight. Even before we shortened the bracelet, our test watch weighed only 105 grams. Thanks to this low overall weight, both the supple link bracelet and the case fit very comfortably on your wrist. And the case is by no means ultra-slim. It’s 14 mm in height and has the typically complex shape of a Grand Seiko.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-340x345.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-570x578.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="1168" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-145030" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-768x779.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-1024x1038.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-570x578.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-340x345.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-320x324.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-205x208.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-255x259.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-940x953.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1613e2de65925eb9a116-620x629.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure>



<p>The Japanese design tradition in general and Grand Seiko’s brand philosophy in particular both take elements of local culture and nature and incorporate them into the design of new products. Some Japanese watch dials evoke the colors of maple leaves in autumn, the texture of birch bark, the grain of snow, or the tracks in the gravel of Zen gardens. In addition, some of Grand Seiko’s movement bridges recall the contours of the famous Mount Fuji or Mount Iwate. The goal is never to produce a realistic representation, but always to create subtle impressions.</p>



<p>The dial of the new model that we tested recalls traditional Japanese sliding doors, which are covered with paper that diffuses incoming light and softens its harshness. The dial’s light, airy, paper-like structure can be recognized by an attentive observer who gets close to the watch’s face. But viewed from arm’s length or farther away, the dial appears white and smooth. This corresponds with the Japanese tradition of subtlety and understatement, while also expressing modest luxury, because the dial’s special surface is visible only at close range.</p>



<p>And speaking of luxury, this watch costs $8,500 and is therefore not one of those models that you might buy on a whim. The harmonious combination of elegant design and versatile functionality mentioned earlier is available for this price. But that’s not all. If you turn the watch over, you’ll see a&nbsp;<em>manufacture</em>&nbsp;movement with numerous technical advantages. The highly efficient, bidirectionally active Magic Lever double-pawl winding system harnesses the rotor’s kinetic energy to keep the tested Grand Seiko Caliber 9S86 running for 55 hours. The manufacturer guarantees precise timekeeping throughout this interval, with precision of between -3 and +5 seconds per day. Among other contributors to the accurate rate, the balance oscillates at a speedy pace of 36,000 rather than the usual 28,800 vibrations per hour. This means that the seconds hand advances through 10 steps per second rather than eight. To put it simply, a higher balance frequency generally means a greater likelihood of precision because the deviations are within a narrower range of the optimum.</p>



<p>On an electronic timing machine, a Witschi Chronoscope X1, our test watch measured a daily loss of 2.3 seconds, confirming that it stayed within the limits specified by Grand Seiko. During a wearing test of several weeks, it settled toward the lower limit of the permissible range with a daily loss of 3 seconds. Loss rather than gain is generally not welcome, but it can be tolerated when it’s as slight as it is here, especially because the values in the six positions cluster within a narrow range of just 4 seconds.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-340x433.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-570x726.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="1468" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-145031" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-768x979.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-1024x1305.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-570x726.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-340x433.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-320x408.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-205x261.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-255x325.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-940x1198.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/aee169ba74cc162fd8e5-620x790.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure>



<p>Grand Seiko not only manufactures common components such as bridges and plates in-house, but also fabricates critical parts such as mainsprings and even hairsprings, for which the manufactory has developed its own high-performance alloys. But individualized solutions are not only found in the depths of the movement, they can be seen on the surface. Peering through the transparent pane of sapphire crystal in the back of our test watch, we didn’t see a standard, semicircular, steel-colored rotor, but instead found a circular, skeletonized component with a gold-colored, irregularly structured surface and an integrated disk with an engraving of the Grand Seiko lion.</p>



<p>The manufactory relies on in-house electrolysis to give the rotor an unconventional color and texture. During the process, a layer of oxide forms on the surface of the titanium rotor. This coating acquires its desired gold tone when its thickness is precisely right. Some may wonder how a circular rotor can create enough inertia by responding to the natural motions of the wearer’s wrist. Quite simply, three rivets join the rotor to an arc-shaped weight that runs around half of the rotor and can only be seen if you look very closely.</p>



<p>If you want a comprehensive description of the Grand Seiko Hi-Beat 36000 GMT 44GS 55th Anniversary Limited Edition, you would need to expand its list of attributes. It is not only elegant and functional, it also offers a variety of individualized solutions ranging from the dial’s special paperlike appearance, to the case and bracelet made from the brand’s proprietary titanium alloy, to the quickly oscillating balance with in-house components. Unfortunately, only 1,200 buyers worldwide will be able to enjoy the versatile SBGJ255 on their wrists — a direct descendent of the 44GS from 1967 that established, once and for all, the Grand Seiko style.</p>



<p><em>To learn more about Grand Seiko, click <a href="https://www.grand-seiko.com/">here</a>, and to subscribe to the WatchTime print magazine, click </em><a href="https://www.watchtime-shop.com/subscription.html"><em>here</em></a><em>. &nbsp;</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p> <em>This article was originally published in the September/October 2022 Issue of the WatchTime print magazine.</em> <em>&nbsp;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/up-close-with-the-grand-seiko-hi-beat-36000-gmt-44gs-55th-anniversary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breitling Unveils a North American Exclusive in the Navitimer B01 Chronograph 43 Limited Edition</title>
		<link>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/breitling-unveils-a-north-american-exclusive-in-the-navitimer-b01-chronograph-43-limited-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/breitling-unveils-a-north-american-exclusive-in-the-navitimer-b01-chronograph-43-limited-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabine Zwettler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breitling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breitling Navitimer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breitling Navitimer B01 Chronograph 42 Limited Edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chronographs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COSC chronometer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Limited Edition Watches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacture movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stainless steel watches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Two-tone Watches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.watchtime.com/?p=168355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Celebrating one of its most sought-after watches, Breitling has announced the release of the Navitimer B01 Chronograph 43 North American Limited Edition— a striking new iteration of the pilot&#8217;s chronograph that has been in existence for ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Celebrating one of its most sought-after watches,<strong> </strong><a href="http://watchtime.com/tag/breitling"><strong>Breitling</strong> </a>has announced the release of the <strong>Navitimer B01 Chronograph 43 North American Limited Edition</strong>— a striking new iteration of the pilot&#8217;s chronograph that has been in existence for more than 70 years. Limited to just 300 individually numbered pieces, this exclusive model is available only in the United States and Canada.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-340x340.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-570x570.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="2048" height="2048" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168360" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM.jpg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-1500x1500.jpg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-570x570.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-340x340.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-320x320.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-205x205.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-255x255.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-1880x1880.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-940x940.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_3quarter_ECOM-620x620.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></figure>



<p>With its&nbsp;anthracite dial, contrasting&nbsp;black sub dials, baton-hour markers and the elegant combination of a&nbsp;stainless steel case&nbsp;and a<strong> </strong>red gold circular slide rule, the new Navitimer reinterprets the legendary silhouette with contemporary refinement. Measuring&nbsp;43mm wide and 13,69mm thick, and paired with a hand-stitched&nbsp;black alligator leather strap, the piece honors its aviation roots. Each watch is engraved with&nbsp;<em>“ONE OF 300”</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>“LIMITED EDITION.”</em></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560-340x255.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="560" height="420" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560.jpg" alt="Breitling Navitimer - vintage" class="wp-image-65873" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560.jpg 560w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560-340x255.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560-320x240.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/Breitling_Navitimer_vintage_560-205x154.jpg 205w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px" /><figcaption><em><sup>Vintage Navitimer</sup></em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Originally designed in 1952 as a wrist-worn instrument for pilots, the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/vintage-eye-for-the-modern-guy-part-12-breitling-navitimer/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/vintage-eye-for-the-modern-guy-part-12-breitling-navitimer/" target="_blank">Navitimer</a> quickly became synonymous with precision and functionality. It was adopted just two years later by the <strong>Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association (AOPA)</strong> as its official timepiece, with the winged AOPA emblem proudly positioned at 12 o’clock. The name “Navitimer”— short for “navigation timer”— soon became legend in cockpit culture.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-340x340.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-570x570.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="2048" height="2048" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168364" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM.jpg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-1500x1500.jpg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-570x570.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-340x340.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-320x320.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-205x205.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-255x255.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-1880x1880.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-940x940.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Back_ECOM-620x620.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></figure>



<p>The transparent case back reveals the&nbsp;beautifully finished, COSC-certified Breitling Manufacture Caliber 01, an in-house column-wheel chronograph movement with a vertical clutch beating at 28,800 vph and enabling the measurement of elapsed times of 1/4th second, 30 minutes, 12 hours. The self-winding movement offers a&nbsp;70-hour power reserve&nbsp;and date indication at 6 o&#8217;clock.</p>



<p>Over the decades, the Navitimer has graced the wrists of&nbsp;commercial pilots, astronauts, and cultural icons alike. From astronaut <strong>Scott Carpenter,</strong> who wore it into space in 1962, to jazz great <strong>Miles Davis</strong> and French provocateur <strong>Serge Gainsbourg</strong>, the watch has captured imaginations far beyond aviation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="3000" height="3000" src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-3000x3000.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168365" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-3000x3000.jpg 3000w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-1500x1500.jpg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-570x570.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-340x340.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-320x320.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-205x205.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-255x255.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-1880x1880.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-940x940.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Breitling_NAVITIMER-B01_CHRONOGRAPH_43_UB01384A1B1P1_Soldier_ECOM-620x620.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></figure>



<p>Available exclusively at&nbsp;Breitling Boutiques,&nbsp;authorized retailers, and&nbsp;Breitling.com&nbsp;in North America, the Navitimer B01 Chronograph 43 North American Limited Edition&nbsp;retails for $12,300.</p>



<p><em>To learn more, visit Breitling, <a href="https://www.breitling.com/us-en/watches/navitimer/navitimer-b01-chronograph-43-my22/UB01384A1B1P1/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.breitling.com/us-en/watches/navitimer/navitimer-b01-chronograph-43-my22/UB01384A1B1P1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/breitling-unveils-a-north-american-exclusive-in-the-navitimer-b01-chronograph-43-limited-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Raymond Weil Expands Millésime Collection with New Variants and a Chronograph</title>
		<link>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/raymond-weil-expands-millesime-collection-with-new-variants-and-a-chronograph/</link>
					<comments>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/raymond-weil-expands-millesime-collection-with-new-variants-and-a-chronograph/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabine Zwettler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dress Watches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geneva fine watchmaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green dial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millésime Central Seconds 35mm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raymond Weil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raymond Weil Millésime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raymond Weil Millésime Chronograph 39mm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raymond Weil Millésime Small Seconds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reverse Panda Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salmon dial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.watchtime.com/?p=168330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hot on the heels of Watches &#38; Wonders 2025, where Raymond Weil drew attention with the debut of its freelancer Complete Calendar, the independent, family-owned Geneva watchmaker— set to mark its 50th anniversary next year— returns to the ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hot on the heels of <strong>Watches &amp; Wonder</strong><em>s </em><strong>2025</strong>, where <strong><a href="https://www.watchtime.com/tag/Raymond-Weil">Raymond Weil</a></strong> drew attention with the debut of its <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/raymond-weil-expands-freelancer-collection-with-two-elegant-complete-calendars/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/raymond-weil-expands-freelancer-collection-with-two-elegant-complete-calendars/" target="_blank"><strong>freelancer Complete Calendar</strong></a>, the independent, family-owned Geneva watchmaker— set to mark its 50th anniversary next year— returns to the spotlight with a refined expansion of its <strong>Millésime</strong> collection. This is the same line that earned the prestigious <strong>Grand Prix de l&#8217;Horlogerie de Genève (GPHG) Challenge Watch Prize</strong> in 2023. Six new smaller iterations of the Millésime join the collection this year, including two models that, for the first time, feature a central seconds hand— marking a subtle yet significant evolution in the line. These are accompanied by a newly introduced chronograph, available in three distinctive variants.</p>



<h2>Millésime Chronograph 39mm</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-340x453.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-570x760.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="887" height="1183" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168336" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR.jpg 887w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-570x760.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-340x453.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-320x427.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-205x273.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-255x340.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_LR-620x827.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 887px) 100vw, 887px" /></figure>



<p>Offered in both stainless steel and rose gold PVD-coated steel, the&nbsp;<strong>Millésime Chronograph</strong> <strong>39mm</strong>&nbsp;delivers a refined interpretation of one of watchmaking’s most enduring genres. Staying true to the collection’s vintage-inspired aesthetic, the watch features a sector-style dial with a classic tri-compax layout in a striking&nbsp;reverse panda&nbsp;configuration, complemented by a tachymeter scale on the flange. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-340x254.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-570x426.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="2339" height="1750" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168338" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR.jpg 2339w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-1500x1122.jpg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-768x575.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-1536x1149.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-2048x1532.jpg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-1024x766.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-570x426.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-340x254.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-320x239.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-205x153.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-255x191.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-1880x1407.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-940x703.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_7765-PC5-20631_CLUPDIAL_RVB_LR-620x464.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 2339px) 100vw, 2339px" /></figure>



<p>Available in black or anthracite, the dial is enhanced by Superluminova coated hour markers and hands for optimal legibility in low light. A domed, box-style sapphire crystal underscores the retro appeal, while the exhibition case back reveals the&nbsp;Sellita-based&nbsp;automatic caliber RW5030 with an impressive 62-hour power reserve.</p>



<p>Water-resistant to 50 meters, the Millésime Chronograph 39mm is available with a leather strap and a bracelet, with pricing starting at $3,625.</p>



<h2>Millésime Small Seconds 35mm</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-340x453.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-570x760.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1875" height="2500" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168342" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01.jpg 1875w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-1125x1500.jpg 1125w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-1024x1365.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-570x760.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-340x453.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-320x427.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-205x273.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-255x340.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-940x1253.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-60521_BEAUTY_SHOT_RVB_01-620x827.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1875px) 100vw, 1875px" /></figure>



<p>Previously available in a 39.5mm diameter, the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/fashion-forward-raymond-weil-introduces-millesime-automatic-small-seconds-denim-blue/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/fashion-forward-raymond-weil-introduces-millesime-automatic-small-seconds-denim-blue/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Millésime Small Seconds</a>&nbsp;collection has been expanded with four new executions in a refined 35mm x 10.25mm case. This reduced size enhances the timepiece&#8217;s elegant character and makes it an ideal unisex option, further emphasizing its dress watch appeal.</p>



<p>Each model is powered by the self-winding RW4250 caliber, based on a Sellita movement, offering a power reserve of 41 hours, and attached to a leather strap. The new models are available in the following combinations:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-340x476.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-570x799.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="850" height="1191" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168343" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR.jpg 850w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-768x1076.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-570x799.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-340x476.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-320x448.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-205x287.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-255x357.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2130-STC-80001_PACKSHOT_RVB_LR-620x869.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></figure>



<ul><li><strong>Ref. 2130-STC-80001</strong>: Salmon dial with a stainless-steel case and grey strap</li><li><strong>Ref. 2130-STC-60001</strong>: Anthracite dial featuring a mint-colored minute track and small seconds, paired with a steel case and patinated brown leather strap</li><li><strong>Ref. 2130-STC-65001</strong>: Silver dial with a stainless-steel case and grey strap</li><li><strong>Ref. 2130-C5S-64001</strong>: Cream dial housed in a rose gold PVD-coated case, burgundy strap, and lugs adorned with 16 lab-grown diamonds</li></ul>



<p>Pricing starts at $1,995.</p>



<h2>Millésime Central Seconds 35mm</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-scaled.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-340x453.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-570x760.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1920" height="2560" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-scaled.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168349" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-scaled.jpg 1920w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-1125x1500.jpg 1125w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-1024x1365.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-570x760.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-340x453.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-320x427.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-205x273.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-255x340.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-1880x2507.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-940x1253.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Raymond_Weil_MILLESIME_2125-ST-52001_LIFESTYLE_01_RVB_LR-620x827.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></figure>



<p>Last but not least, Raymond Weil introduces a fresh perspective to the collection with the <strong>Millésime Central Seconds 35mm</strong>. Featuring sector dials with the collection’s signature contrasting finishes, these elegant timepieces are offered in sage green <strong>(ref. 2125-ST-52011)</strong> and cream <strong>(ref. 2125-STS-64001)</strong>— the latter distinguished by lugs adorned with 16 lab-grown diamonds, adding a touch of refined sophistication. </p>



<p>Slimmer than their small seconds counterparts, the 9.18mm-thick steel cases house the Sellita-based self-winding caliber RW4200, which delivers a 41-hour power reserve. Completing the look is a five-link stainless steel bracelet, adding a sporty touch.</p>



<p>Pricing starts at $1,750.</p>



<p><em>To learn more, visit Raymond Weil, <a href="https://www.raymond-weil.us/collections/collection/millesime-collection/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.raymond-weil.us/collections/collection/millesime-collection/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/raymond-weil-expands-millesime-collection-with-new-variants-and-a-chronograph/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making a Case for Collecting Quartz &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/making-a-case-for-collecting-quartz-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/making-a-case-for-collecting-quartz-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin Green]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breitling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F.P. Journe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Seiko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patek Philippe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quartz movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quartz Watches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.watchtime.com/?p=164947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Part I of “Making a Case for Collecting Quartz” (February 2023 WatchTime), we focused on how this then innovative technology came to life and the pioneers that contributed to this. These were exciting and challenging times that would mean ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In <a href="https://www.watchtime.com/featured/making-a-case-for-collecting-quartz/">Part I</a> of “Making a Case for Collecting Quartz” (February 2023 WatchTime), we focused on how this then innovative technology came to life and the pioneers that contributed to this. These were exciting and challenging times that would mean significant changes in the watch industry as a whole and those in Switzerland especially. The unique thing about this situation is that the superior new technology didn’t take over the entire market. Eventually, it seemed to go that way, but in an exciting plot twist, the quartz technology also brought renewed appreciation for mechanical movements.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e-340x547.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="426" height="685" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164960" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e.jpg 426w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e-340x547.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e-320x515.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e-205x330.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d66c0bad517bdb28517e-255x410.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 426px) 100vw, 426px" /></figure></div>



<p>After the dust settled from the ‘Quartz Crisis,’ this resulted in, for many brands, a new status quo. They continued to make mechanical watches but also offered models with quartz movements. For consumers, this was great news, as they could pick whatever suited their needs best. Quartz movements offered reliability and precision appropriate to that of a high-end brand, without having to deal with the challenges that mechanical watches have. Old-school aficionados could, at their turn, still opt for a mechanical timepiece that needed more care and attention to keep running, all with a charm of its own.</p>



<p><em><strong>When is Quartz Collectible?</strong>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>While it is obvious that some of the pioneers are collectible watches, the water gets a bit muddy in the decades after. First, it is essential to point out that collectability has little to do with value, if anything at all. Quartz watches are not at the top of the highest earners at auction houses, but if we compare this to cars, neither are the VW Beetle or Citroën 2CV. Collectability is more about offering something special and appealing, with a story worth telling.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow.png, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-340x340.png, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-570x570.png, (medium)]" loading="lazy" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow.png" alt="" class="wp-image-164950" width="476" height="476" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow.png 800w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-300x300.png 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-768x768.png 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-570x570.png 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-340x340.png 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-320x320.png 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-205x205.png 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-255x255.png 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Ginos_Dream_Yellow-620x620.png 620w" sizes="(max-width: 476px) 100vw, 476px" /></figure></div>



<p>This is also where things start to differentiate when it comes to quartz watches and their various degrees of collectability. It is not a right or wrong question, as it is still the collector who decides what to collect, but some brands and/or models are simply positioned in such a way that they are worth mentioning here.</p>



<p><em><strong>F.P. Journe and the Unexpected Gem</strong>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>It was quite astonishing to see François-Paul Journe launch a quartz watch. As a master watchmaker, he played an essential role in the renaissance of mechanical timepieces, often pushing the boundaries of what was technically possible further away. His approach to quartz came in a similar mindset, as both from an aesthetical and technical point of view the Elégante, as he called this model, is exceptional.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection.png, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-340x340.png, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-570x570.png, (medium)]" loading="lazy" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection.png" alt="" class="wp-image-164949" width="468" height="468" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection.png 800w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-300x300.png 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-768x768.png 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-570x570.png 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-340x340.png 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-320x320.png 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-205x205.png 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-255x255.png 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/EL_tit_ctc_Noir_fb_Collection-620x620.png 620w" sizes="(max-width: 468px) 100vw, 468px" /></figure></div>



<p>He opted for a tortue-shaped case, reminiscent of the tortoiseshell, hence the name. This was already an interesting choice, as previously, F.P. Journe used similarly shaped cases for its Vagabondage collection, which came with unusual mechanical movements and time displays. For the Elégante the look is slightly more traditional, featuring a regular-style dial with Arabic numerals and a subdial at 6 o&#8217;clock for the seconds. Right next to it is a little cut-out where you can see something that looks like a small oscillating weight. It is, in fact, a motion detector. Once it detects no motion for 35 minutes, it freezes the hands while the microprocessor continues to keep the correct time. Once motion is detected again, the watch sets itself, and off you go. When worn daily, the Elégante has a battery life of about eight years but can extend this in power-saving mode to 18.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-340x189.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-570x317.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164952" width="647" height="360" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1.jpg 800w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-768x427.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-570x317.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-340x189.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-320x178.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-205x114.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-255x142.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/FPJourne-Mouvement-Calibre-1210_0-1-620x345.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 647px) 100vw, 647px" /></figure></div>



<p>Another progressive feature you wouldn’t expect from an F.P. Journe is that the dial is actually made of Super-LumiNova, giving quite a spectacular effect in low-light conditions. For the rest, the Elégante is finished in the same way as its mechanical counterparts. F.P. Journe even fitted the quartz movement with pink-gold bridges, a signature feature of the brand. The Elégante is available in 40 mm and 48 mm, both featuring a case made of titanium and fitted with rubber straps. This extends the wearing comfort and gives an additional sportive touch to this quartz watch. The Elégante, first and foremost, shows that not all quartz watches are created equal, and that even this technology has a place in haute horlogerie when approached in a similar fashion as its mechanical siblings.</p>



<p><em><strong>Grand Seiko’s Quest for Understated Excellence</strong>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>One of the first and most commonly made assumptions about quartz movements is that they are all created equal. As with mechanical calibers, this is not the case. A great example of this are the Grand Seikos fitted with Caliber 9F Quartz. They form the brand’s entry level and offer a refined sense of understatement. They are part of Grand Seiko’s Heritage collection, which is for a good reason, as they represent the brand’s focus on excellence in quartz movements.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="3000" height="1482" src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-3000x1482.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164953" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-3000x1482.jpg 3000w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-1500x741.jpg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-768x379.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-1536x759.jpg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-2048x1012.jpg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-1024x506.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-570x282.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-340x168.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-320x158.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-205x101.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-255x126.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-1880x929.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-940x464.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/01_SBGP001_5pc-620x306.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></figure>



<p>First and foremost is that Caliber 9F is created to be a serviceable movement. This sounds like a given, but many quartz movements are still made in such a way that when anything is wrong, a new movement must be put inside the watch. With Caliber 9F, the entire movement can come apart and be serviced, also allowing individual parts to be replaced. Like its mechanical siblings, Grand Seiko’s quartz calibers are assembled entirely by hand. However, the brand goes even further than that.</p>



<p>Grand Seiko grows its own quartz crystals and ages them. When the crystals are cut and finished, they test their performance. Only the best are up to being used in a Caliber 9F.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-340x307.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-570x514.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="986" height="889" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164954" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271.jpg 986w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-768x692.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-570x514.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-340x307.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-320x289.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-205x185.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-255x230.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-940x848.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/2eaf1bfdf8c499b13271-620x559.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 986px) 100vw, 986px" /></figure>



<p>Even there, engineers pair the crystal specifically with an integrated circuit to ensure the best result. Combined with the thermo-compensation system, which measures the ambient temperature and adjusts any deviation in the oscillation frequency caused by changes in this, the accuracy of a Caliber 9F is +/- 10 seconds a year. This is substantially better than the average quartz movement.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G.png, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-340x340.png, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-570x570.png, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1102" height="1102" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G.png" alt="" class="wp-image-164955" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G.png 1102w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-300x300.png 300w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-768x768.png 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-570x570.png 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-340x340.png 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-320x320.png 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-205x205.png 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-255x255.png 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-940x940.png 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/SBGX261G-620x620.png 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1102px) 100vw, 1102px" /></figure>



<p>Grand Seiko’s great care in crafting Caliber 9F also becomes evident when you see the finishing of the movement. Its clever construction is designed in such a way that during regular battery changes, dust can’t enter the module, once again underscoring the tremendous effort Grand Seiko put into it to guarantee the utmost performance. So, the only way in which the models fitted with Caliber 9F may form the entry level of Grand Seiko is financially, as they are otherwise among the most refined and well-engineered quartz movements in the world.</p>



<p><em><strong>Breitlings Believe in Quartz</strong>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Breitling is one of those brands that has embraced quartz for a substantial part of its collection. With their focus on aviation and the slogan ‘Instruments for professionals,’ this makes all the more sense. Breitling has also always been proud of its achievements in this area, of which a new chapter started in 1999. It was that year when the brand announced that it would COSC certify 100 percent of its production. This means that each and every Breitling produced from then on is chronometer-certified, and that includes the ones with quartz movements.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-340x161.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-570x270.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="546" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164956" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-768x364.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-1024x485.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-570x270.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-340x161.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-320x152.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-205x97.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-255x121.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-940x446.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/d609994e98c4b3c54726-620x294.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure>



<p>This is quite exceptional because not many brands go through the effort (and cost) of obtaining this type of certification for a quartz movement. Generally, they are deemed accurate enough, rendering the COSC certification as something stating the obvious. Breitling’s approach is different, as their focus on crafting ‘instruments for professionals’ also means that their performance is verified by an independent authority. COSC is quite rigorous in its approach toward quartz movements, which must be thermo-compensated and fully encapsulated against any form of moisture. Quartz movements that want to earn a chronometer certification are tested for 13 days in one position, during which they are exposed to three different temperatures and four different humidity levels, all combined with stringent tolerances. Breitling met this challenge by introducing the SuperQuartz movements at the beginning of the new millennium. Thanks to the aforementioned thermo-compensation and capsulation against moisture, these movements are about 10 times as accurate as a regular quartz movement.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-340x249.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-570x417.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="866" height="633" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164957" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052.jpg 866w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-768x561.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-570x417.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-340x249.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-320x234.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-205x150.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-255x186.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/1fc347d732dd938eb052-620x453.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 866px) 100vw, 866px" /></figure>



<p>As quartz is a way of life for Breitling, next to their still numerous offerings with mechanical movements, this has also resulted in quite a few watches that have earned quite the reputation. Many of them combine an analog time display with digital screens. This allows them to offer additional functions such as multiple time zones, alarm and chronograph. The Aerospace is a great example of this, and it is also a watch that Breitling continued to evolve over the decades that it is part of its collection. Another memorable watch is the Emergency, which has a similar look as the Aerospace but combines this with a built-in distress beacon. While these additional functions don’t add, or take away, from the performance of the quartz movement, they do display what more is possible. For Breitling, quartz technology is simply another way to meet the needs of professionals.</p>



<p><em><strong>Patek Philippe’s Passion for Precision</strong>&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>One comment I often hear is that ladies prefer quartz over mechanical, as you can just grab these watches, put them on, and they are always right on time until you have to change the battery again. Whether this is true or not depends on the lady, and quite frankly, I also know quite a few avid mechanical watch collectors who are male and also prefer to have one or more quartz watches at hand for that exact same reason. The fact of the matter is that quite a few watches for ladies are fitted with quartz movements.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-340x510.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-570x855.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1139" height="1709" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164958" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca.jpg 1139w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-1000x1500.jpg 1000w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-570x855.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-340x510.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-320x480.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-205x308.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-255x383.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-940x1410.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7d875c506b3a1f286cca-620x930.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1139px) 100vw, 1139px" /></figure>



<p>In some cases, the quartz movement is also part of the legacy. At the turn of the millennium, in 1999, Patek Philippe launched the Twenty~4. This rectangular, bracelet-style watch offered a timeless sense of feminine elegance and would become one of the pillars of the Patek Philippe collection. Offered in both stainless steel and precious metal, it had a casual flair that still makes it very contemporary. While Patek Philippe has since added round-shaped mechanical watches to the collection, the rectangular Twenty~4 is still going strong, with a row of diamonds flanking each side of the dial. This is perhaps also a great example of a timepiece where a quartz movement is right at home. While some still might prefer a small manual-wound movement of sorts ticking inside, the quartz caliber is more aligned with the character of the watch, also testified by the success of the Twenty~4.</p>



<p>This is not the only collection in which Patek Philippe offers quartz movements, as the Nautilus and Aquanaut are also available powered by a battery. They are fitted with Caliber E 23-250 S C, and like F.P. Journe, brands like Patek Philippe do not abandon the standards they hold high when making a movement with a battery. This particular caliber consists of 80 parts, with eight of them being synthetic rubies, also known as jewels. While they play an important role in mechanical watches to limit friction in the moving parts, there is much less movement inside a quartz caliber. That brands like Patek Philippe still utilize them is a sign of quality, going that extra mile to make something good even better. We also see this with the bridges on Caliber E 23-250 S C. They are chamfered and decorated with Geneva stripes, obtaining a look and finish similar to that of Patek Philippe’s mechanical movements.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4.jpg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-340x525.jpg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-570x881.jpg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="1152" height="1780" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-164959" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4.jpg 1152w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-971x1500.jpg 971w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-768x1187.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-994x1536.jpg 994w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-1024x1582.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-570x881.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-340x525.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-320x494.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-205x317.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-255x394.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-940x1452.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/8579e5eba9f6c174d0a4-620x958.jpg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /></figure>



<p>Quartz movements also have a few benefits up their sleeves, and Patek Philippe is also taking advantage of those. In general, a quartz movement can more easily be made slimmer than its mechanical counterpart with the same functions. A slimmer movement means that you can also create a watch whose case is not as thick as it otherwise would have been. This can offer increased elegance and wearing comfort. Patek Philippe also fitted the Aquanaut Luce with Caliber E 23-250 S FUS 24H. This movement is made along the lines of Caliber E 23-250 S C, but showing two time zones simultaneously combined with a day/night indication for the home time through a window at 6 o&#8217;clock. This turns the Aquanaut Luce into a convenient and stylish travel watch. Its added complication is an interesting one and shows that quartz movements have proven their added value in the world of haute horlogerie and earned their place. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><em>This article is from the WatchTime Archives and was originally published in the March / April 2023 Issue.</em> <em>To subscribe to WatchTime Magazine,&nbsp;<a href="http://watchtime-shop.com/">click here</a>.</em> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/making-a-case-for-collecting-quartz-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Business News: Corum Under New Ownership</title>
		<link>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/business-news-corum-under-new-ownership/</link>
					<comments>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/business-news-corum-under-new-ownership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabine Zwettler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiss Watch Industry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.watchtime.com/?p=168375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Storied Swiss watchmaker Corum, founded in 1955 and renowned for its bold design and horological innovation, announces its return to Swiss ownership. The management buy-out was led by Haso Mehmedovic, Corum’s International Sales Director, in ...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Storied Swiss watchmaker <strong><a href="http://watchtime.com/tag/corum">Corum</a></strong>, founded in 1955 and renowned for its bold design and horological innovation, announces its return to Swiss ownership. The management buy-out was led by <strong>Haso Mehmedovic</strong>, Corum’s International Sales Director, in partnership with a group of Swiss investors. Mehmedovic, who began his career at Corum 15 years ago as a watchmaker, will assume the role of CEO and Chairman of the Board.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="2322" height="3000" src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-2322x3000.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-168379" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-2322x3000.jpg 2322w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-1161x1500.jpg 1161w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-768x992.jpg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-1189x1536.jpg 1189w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-1585x2048.jpg 1585w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-1024x1323.jpg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-570x736.jpg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-340x439.jpg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-320x413.jpg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-205x265.jpg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-255x329.jpg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-1880x2429.jpg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-940x1214.jpg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-620x801.jpg 620w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum_Haso_Mehmedovic-scaled.jpg 1981w" sizes="(max-width: 2322px) 100vw, 2322px" /></figure>



<p>The acquisition was completed in a spirit of collaboration and mutual respect with&nbsp;<strong>Citychamp Watch &amp; Jewellery Group Limited</strong>, the Hong Kong-listed parent company that has owned Corum since 2013. Citychamp, which remains active in the Swiss watch industry through brands such as <strong>Eterna</strong>, has agreed to support a smooth transition, ensuring continuity and a strong foundation for the future.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113.jpeg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-340x245.jpeg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-570x412.jpeg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="2126" height="1535" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-168382" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113.jpeg 2126w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-1500x1083.jpeg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-768x555.jpeg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-1536x1109.jpeg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-2048x1479.jpeg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-1024x739.jpeg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-570x412.jpeg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-340x245.jpeg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-320x231.jpeg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-205x148.jpeg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-255x184.jpeg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-1880x1357.jpeg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-940x679.jpeg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-GoldenBridge-CO113-620x448.jpeg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 2126px) 100vw, 2126px" /></figure>



<p>According to the brand, 2025 will be a year of consolidation, with a focus on strengthening Corum’s flagship collections and reaffirming the brand’s distinct identity. The leadership team is committed to preserving the company’s spirit of innovation while honoring its rich legacy. A&nbsp;global relaunch is planned for mid-2026, highlighting Corum’s core values and celebrated design ethos. </p>



<p>The brand’s current distribution network, which includes just under 300 watch retailers worldwide, will be reinforced, with curated partnerships to ensure high-quality after-sales service for its clients.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;We have a tremendous opportunity to restore Corum’s rightful place in Swiss watchmaking, guided by bold creativity, innovation, and the brand’s unique DNA. As someone who started my career with Corum in 2011 and grew alongside it, I’m proud to lead this next chapter with a dedicated team and a long-term vision.&#8221;</p><cite><strong>Haso Mehmedovic</strong></cite></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-interchange="[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica.jpeg, (default)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-340x245.jpeg, (small)],[https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-570x412.jpeg, (medium)]" loading="lazy" width="2126" height="1535" data-old-src="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-168380" srcset="https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica.jpeg 2126w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-1500x1083.jpeg 1500w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-768x555.jpeg 768w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-1536x1109.jpeg 1536w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-2048x1479.jpeg 2048w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-1024x739.jpeg 1024w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-570x412.jpeg 570w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-340x245.jpeg 340w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-320x231.jpeg 320w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-205x148.jpeg 205w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-255x184.jpeg 255w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-1880x1357.jpeg 1880w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-940x679.jpeg 940w, https://www.watchtime.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Corum-Admiral46-Acoustica-620x448.jpeg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 2126px) 100vw, 2126px" /></figure>



<p>Among Corum’s most iconic creations are the <strong>Golden Bridge</strong>, renowned for its revolutionary linear movement,  the <strong>Bubble</strong>, instantly recognizable by its bold 11 mm domed crystal and the <strong>Admiral</strong>, a maritime masterpiece featuring complications like tides, amplitudes, moon phases, and tidal currents.</p>



<p><em>To learn more, visit Corum, <a href="https://www.corum-watches.com" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.corum-watches.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.watchtime.com/featured/business-news-corum-under-new-ownership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
